<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:55:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling from Manali to Leh - An FAQ</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cycling-from-manali-to-leh-an-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cycling-from-manali-to-leh-an-faq/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  So, you cycled from Manali to Leh? Who is &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;? How did you decide to do this? What is the maximum elevation you cycled to? How long did the whole ride take? Was it really hard? Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t you finish the ride? So, you do really need a support vehicle? How much did the support vehicle cost you? Did you carry your own bikes? Did the flights charge you for the bikes? Would you recommend me to carry my bike? What cycle spares/tools did you carry? What sort of preparation did you do for this ride? Can you share your ride plan? What was a typical day during the trip, like? What was the most enjoyable part of the ride? What was the most challenging part of the ride? You keep saying it was cold, how cold was it really? Did you meet any interesting people en-route? Would you do this again? If yes, which part of the year would you do it? If not, what other routes would you try? Do you have any pictures that you can share?  So, you cycled from Manali to Leh? Well, Not really. We cycled from Kalath to Whiskey Nala &amp;ndash; a distance of 280km &amp;ndash; which is about 60% of the Manali-Leh route.
Who is &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;? Vivek and I were on the bikes. Shabu was our guide helping us fix our bikes and fixing up our meals, but more than anything else, ensuring that we don&amp;rsquo;t freeze to death. Susheel was driving along and cheering us.
How did you decide to do this? Vivek and I were going to Coorg with Prats and Addy, and Prats told us a whole lot of stories of her adventures in the mountains. Not sure how bicycles came into the picture, but as soon as they did, both of us got really excited about it. This was on some sort of a bucket list for me, ever since I read Vatsap&amp;rsquo;s cycling story many years ago. Soon, after we were back in town, the ball was set rolling&amp;hellip;
What is the maximum elevation you cycled to? We started off at around 1.8km and went up to about 5km in a span of 5 days. We also spent a day in Manali, getting our cycles fixed and acclimatizing. You can see the elevation profile here.
How long did the whole ride take? Our plan was to finish the whole distance in 7 days. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get to our designated camp on the 5th day, and had to use the support car to get to camp before it got dark. We decided to end the ride once we took our bikes off the road.
Was it really hard? Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t you finish the ride? We expected the primary challenges to be:
 the altitude and lack of oxygen the fatigue from riding day after day after day&amp;hellip;  But, cold played a much bigger role than we thought it would. As we got higher and higher, it got so cold that we spent a significant amount of energy and brain cycles on trying to fight the cold, rather than enjoying the views or pushing ourselves to keep going despite the non-cold-related discomfort.
So, you do really need a support vehicle? Not really, if you were riding in better weather or were better prepared. The Manali to Leh route usually has a lot of temporary shops setup during the season, where you could crash, if it was too cold to just crash in your tent. Since, we were going after the season had almost ended, many of these shops were no longer open, and having the support car turned out to be quite useful on the last day.
How much did the support vehicle cost you? It turned out to be quite an expense for something we originally didn&amp;rsquo;t have in mind. We spent about 20k on the vehicle, fuel and the driver&amp;rsquo;s fee. We also paid our guide + cook + bicycle expert, separately.
Did you carry your own bikes? Yes.
 Flew from Bengaluru to Delhi Took a bus from Delhi to Manali Carried the bikes on the support car from Whiskey Nala to Leh Flew back from Leh to Delhi  Did the flights charge you for the bikes? The carrier (IndiGo) from BLR to DEL charged us a handling fees of Rs. 1000. The carrier (Vistara) on the return journey didn&amp;rsquo;t.
Would you recommend me to carry my bike? You could find bikes on rent, both in Manali and Leh, for about 500 to 700 per day. It would cost about 5-7k, based on how you plan your ride, to rent a bike. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to make arrangements to get the bike returned back to the place you rent it from &amp;ndash; this can get a little tricky.
If you already own a bike, and can it packed in a proper box, I would highly recommend that. The derailleurs, the shifters, and other such moving parts need to be well packed and guarded. Use a box or a cycling bag to put it in. Get professional help from a cycle retailer nearby, if required. This is one thing you cannot take any chances on, or your whole trip may be jeopardized!
We hadn&amp;rsquo;t paid enough attention to packing our bikes, and one of our bikes took quite some beating on the way to Delhi. On the way back, we managed to get the bike packed in a box and it was a breeze.
What cycle spares/tools did you carry? We were sort of ill prepared in this department. We only had the following:
 Hand pump Puncture kit Spare tubes (2 nos.) Allen key set  Based on advice from Shabu, I think you should also take these things:
 Brake cables Gear cables Spare tyre (1 Nos.) Brake shoes/pads Few spokes Chain oil  What sort of preparation did you do for this ride? We did a handful of 50-100km rides on weekends before this one. The only real elevation training/trial that we did was the Kalhatti climb, one weekend before this ride. This turned out to be pretty useful, and we found all the other climbs during this ride much less steeper than some of the Kalhatti ones.
Can you share your ride plan? What we actually rode    Day Start End Distance Elevation gain Comments     0 Kalath - -  Fix cycles and acclimatize   1 Kalath Marhi 45km 1675m Prepare to cross Rohtang!   2 Marhi Keylong 80km -210m Crossed Rohtang (3970m)   3 Keylong Patseo 48km +644m Easy ride; Deepak Tal!   4 Patseo Sarchu 64km +522m Crossed Baralachala(4902m)!   5 Sarchu Whiskey Nala 48km +465m Gata loops &amp;amp; Nakeela(4924m)    Original plan    Day Start End Distance Elevation gain Comments     5 Sarchu Pang 73km +225m Gata-loops, Nakeela(4924m) &amp;amp; Lachung La(5065m)   6 Pang Lato 103km -530m Moore Plains, Tanglang La (5328m)   7 Lato Leh 70km -600m Lots of downhill!    What was a typical day during the trip, like?  Wake up between 7 and 8, depending on when you can see/feel the warm sun. Laze in bed if you woke up too early, and the sun hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet warmed the place up. Eat porridge, and a few slices of bread with peanut butter. Pack ourselves up in as many layers of clothing as we can, while still being able to pedal. Check the bikes for any loose/fallen-off/broken parts, blow, etc. Start pedaling away - usually between 9 and 10. It&amp;rsquo;s too cold to start earlier. Keep adjusting the clothing, based on how cold/warm it is, and the wind chill. Keep munching, or sipping on some water (plain or mixed with some energizer). Continue pedaling, and start looking at the milestones a little more carefully. Lunch is on our mind, already. Lunch at around 1:30pm - usually, a couple of boiled eggs, and a potato. May be a chocolate, and some Frooti. More pedaling. The kilometers start getting harder, the chill is getting harsher. Huff and puff, and reach our camp for the day. Hi-fives! We&amp;rsquo;d try and reach the camp while there is still some sunlight there to keep us warm. Stretch it out, and switch into dry, warm clothes. Grab a quick snack - whole packets of biscuits would just disappear, alongside some tea. Talk, walk around, ponder about life, think about the day that&amp;rsquo;s been, think about the day that is to come, and all that jazz. Eat dinner - dal and rice, mostly. Sleep like logs. Unless, there&amp;rsquo;s a rat in the room that&amp;rsquo;s attacking our dry fruits.  What was the most enjoyable part of the ride?  I really enjoyed sitting at Deepak Tal, and just looking at the clear water The climb to Baralacha La was the most challenging part of the ride. We could see that the weather was really bad in all the peaks around us, and it was getting really cold. Briefly, it was even snowing very lightly and we could see tiny snow flakes floating in front of us. The feeling of reaching the top of passes was quite thrilling, for both Rohtang and Baralacha La. Nakee La, not so much, since we still had about 30km ahead of us to finish the day. It was humbling to see all the BRO folks working to keep the roads open and functional! A big salute to them! Each time we had a truck or some bikers pass by, we would wave at them or show thumbs up, and it would give us some additional energy to keep pushing ahead. The tree covered road in Sissu was just mind blowingly beautiful, with all the trees golden and yellow, preparing for the fall. It was also nice to turn 30, in the hills. Vivek tried to make it as special, for me, as he could.  What was the most challenging part of the ride? The cold. (See, the answer on why we didn&amp;rsquo;t finish the ride).
You keep saying it was cold, how cold was it really? On the night we camped at Sarchu, the water in our bottles and unwashed cups had frozen. We had gone to sub zero temperatures on many nights, it looks like. The winds during the day were quite chilly, and got worse as we gained altitude.
Did you meet any interesting people en-route?  We met a guy from Slovenia who has been taking a couple or so months off for the past 10 years. He was riding around with a 55kg weighing bike for the past 3 weeks, and was going from Leh to Manali, when we met him. He had a lot of stories to tell &amp;ndash; including recommending that we go cycling in Iceland, and enjoy watching the Northern lights from hot water baths.
 Shabu himself had a lot of stories to tell about all the people he had taken on this ride - from guys with a $6k bike to a 70 year old doing the route his 4th time to the guy who would eat only olive oil mixed in rice to safeguard his tummy, and more!
 All the aachos and aamas in the shops/guest houses/etc that we went to were really nice to us. Most of the folks in the shops were planning to leave in a few days after we had met them since it had gotten really cold.
 We had our camp-site at Marhi in the compound of a HP state guest house. The care taker walks up to us, while we are setting up the tent, and says, &amp;ldquo;Idhar kahi par bhi baithna mana hai, 10 hazaar ka fine lag jaayega. Udhar toilet bana hua hai&amp;rdquo;, pointing to the public toilets in a distance, &amp;ldquo;paisa nahi lagega&amp;rdquo;. We had a good laugh, and ended up wondering if it was Swach Bharat showing some effect.
  We probably would&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot more people, and met a lot more interesting people, if we were there in better weather and didn&amp;rsquo;t have a support vehicle taking care of us. Next time!
Would you do this again? May be. We feel like we got a taste of the challenge of the ride, and the rest of the route wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be anymore challenging than what we already saw, if we did it in better weather. But, the better weather would also mean more traffic and noise on the road.
If yes, which part of the year would you do it? Late August to mid-September might be a better time. We&amp;rsquo;d also need to look out for rains and land-slides, though.
If not, what other routes would you try?  Cycling around Europe sounds like a fun thing to try Rides in the western ghats and/or Kerala seem promising A Tour of Meghalaya was something a friend suggested Pushing that a little more, ride all the way to Singapore/Indonesia, starting at home  Do you have any pictures that you can share? A post shared by Punch (@punchagan) on Nov 6, 2017 at 2:44am PST
  You can find some pictures and videos here. The album also includes some pictures from our practice rides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs frame as a pop-up input</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/emacs-frame-as-a-pop-up-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 22:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/emacs-frame-as-a-pop-up-input/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try using a dialog box/pop-up window as a prompt to remind me to periodically make journal entries. I had the following requirements:
 Simple, light-weight dialog box that allows text of arbitrary length Ability to launch the dialog from the shell Ability to have some placeholder or template text, each time the dialog is shown Save the input text to a specific org-mode file Write as little code of my own, as possible, to do this  I had initially thought about using a tool like zenity, or write a simple dialog box in Python using Qt, wx or even tk, and then yank the input text at the desired location. This probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have turned out to be too hard, but getting things to look and work exactly the way I wanted would have required more code than I was willing to write or maintain.
After avoiding doing this for a while, I finally realized that I could simply use Emacs with a new frame with the appropriate dimensions, and with the correct file/buffer open to the desired location. This would
 eliminate the need for me to write the UI myself eliminate the need to do text manipulation in code, to yank it at the right place, in the right form. By directly opening up the editor at the required location, the onus is on me (as a text inputting user) to put it in, the way I want it. additionally provide me the comfort of being able to write with the full power of Emacs - keybindings and all that jazz. let me leverage elisp to do essentially whatever I want with the buffer being displayed as the dialog box.  I ended up with a command that looks something like this
emacsclient -c -n\ -F &#39;((title . &amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;) (left . (+ 550)) (top . (+ 400)) (width . 110) (height . 12))&#39;\ -e &#39;(pc/open-journal-buffer)&#39;   This worked pretty nicely, except for the fact that with gnome-shell, the pop-up frame doesn&amp;rsquo;t always appear raised. It often gets hidden in the Emacs windows group, and the whole idea of the pop-up acting as a reminder goes for a toss! But, thanks to this Ask Ubuntu post, I could fix this pretty easily.
emacsclient -c -n\ -F &#39;((title . &amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;) (left . (+ 550)) (top . (+ 400)) (width . 110) (height . 12))&#39;\ -e &#39;(progn (pc/open-journal-buffer) (raise-frame) (x-focus-frame (selected-frame)))&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-09-04</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</guid>
      <description>This week was a busy one, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really consume too much web content.
A colleague mentioned that he was reading the book &amp;ndash; The Millennial Project: Colonizing the Galaxy in Eight Easy Steps and it seemed to have some interesting ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across before.
The Berklee Indian Ensemble performed at the Bengaluru Ganesh Utsava and I went along with Sunil to their performance, which we thoroughly loved.
I liked some of Chet Baker instrumentals that I listened to this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-28</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</guid>
      <description>I liked this article advising developers on having healthy relationships. Most of it is common sense stuff &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Whether it be a side project or main project, understand that sacrificing relationships isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it.&amp;rdquo;
I really enjoyed this article by Priyanka on how she started talking to Auto Drivers. She shares a bunch of stories of drivers she talked to, that makes me wonder how many more such stories just go unheard, because I don&amp;rsquo;t talk.
@scopatz wrote up a nice argument explaining why @github should add back BSD to the list of licenses shown on the site. It taught me a thing or two about BSD and MIT.
I enjoyed spending the weekend at @mavin&amp;rsquo;s place, discussing continuous improvement in life, among other things. Also, had a lot of fun playing Psyche. The game is so addictive, but the app is not all that great. Someone should make a more robust app for this, or something that piggybacks on an existing network service like Telegram or Facebook chat or Google hangouts.
Falling In Love At A Coffee Shop by Landon Pigg is a lovely song, that I discovered this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-21</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</guid>
      <description>Vox has a nice short video on shutting up about the y-axis &amp;ndash; It&amp;rsquo;s long past time to say no to y-axis fundamentalism, they say.
The New York Times has a great visual history of which countries have dominated the Summer Olympics.
This story of Dipa by ESPN is an inspirational read.
An old post on a Frameless Geodesic Dome that Bruce Hauman (of Figwheel fame) built himself is very cool!
This article on India&amp;rsquo;s Gozoomo shutting down shop and returning VC money is heartening and gives me some hope about startups in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-14</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</guid>
      <description>NYTimes has been doing some amazing visualizations for the Olympics and this time lapse visualization of Bolt&amp;rsquo;s 100m Gold is great!
The History Project produced a book called Partitioned Histories that tries to contrast the narratives of India and Pakistan on their histories using school history text books. What a great idea!
This video about the Sunshine Orchestra being trained and tutored by Rahman and his KM Music Conservatory is touching.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; posts on how to decide and think about what to work on are great. &amp;ldquo;Even reliably recognizing good ideas is hard!&amp;rdquo;, she says, and this resonates with me. Writing a release email as a way to think about why you are doing something is great!
Jasdev wrote about his monthly check-ins with friends. I thought they were such a great idea - simple, yet, powerful. &amp;ldquo;The only regret I have about these checkins is not starting sooner.&amp;ldquo;, he writes.
This Vox article on America&amp;rsquo;s increasing wealth gap along racial lines is really well done and thought provoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-07</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</guid>
      <description>Great visualizations about how global temperatures have been changing in the last ~165 years. If you are still a global warming skeptic, you definitely must see them.
These visualizations of Michael Phelps&amp;rsquo; performances at Olympics over the years by NYTimes are great, too!
I came across these delightful videos (1, 2) of girls and boys playing cricket at Haji Public School. Look ma, no sexism in coverage of sports.
This (Telugu) interview of Dr Jayaprakash Narayan is truly inspiring. Also, YouTube recommended his conversation with Sadhguru Jaggi Vasudev, which was unexpectedly insightful, and covers a wide variety of topics &amp;ndash; spirituality, religion, social organizations, politics, socialism vs. capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-31</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Lots of Olympics stuff this week!
I really liked this ad - Rukna Nahi Hai - wishing all the Olympians a wonderfully spirited competition, at Rio. Go!
Brazilian marathoner Vanderlei Cordeiro de Lima, the man who lit the Olympic flame, inspires me with his spirit.
This story of Mohan Kumar from Ambattur, a Chennai suburb is inspiring. &amp;ldquo;Now I am on the relay team. But in the next Olympics, I want to qualify for the individual event. That&amp;rsquo;s my aim.&amp;ldquo;, he says.
@vandith recommended the Nike+ Training App to me and I really like it. They have some amazing workouts and pretty neat personalized workout plans.
Coke Studio Pakistan is trying a delightful experiment with their show this time &amp;ndash; they are trying to use lights and vibrations to let the hearing-impaired experience the music on their show better!
Sainath&amp;rsquo;s keynote at Film Writers Association conference was yet another of his thought-provoking speeches. He sends you down a spiral of thought, when he says, &amp;ldquo;How agonised we are when people die, and how untroubled we are by how they live&amp;rdquo;. I also enjoyed watching his (long) casual chat from an year ago, talking about his life and influences on him.
David Sassoon the founder of InsideClimate News writes about Non-Profit journalism, the need for it, and how to have more of it. He writes about it in the American context, but India has its own share of troubles. I consume quite a bit of news from independent sources, but don&amp;rsquo;t really contribute to keep them going. I should turn this around.
A bunch of residents of Urur Olcott Kuppam in Chennai responded to media&amp;rsquo;s broken coverage of TM Krishna&amp;rsquo;s Magsaysay award. I really liked how assertive they were about their role in the music festival, its role in their lives, and in clarifying how they see their fishing village as opposed to how the media portrayed it. They don&amp;rsquo;t mince any words.
You can find my older weekly posts like this here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-24</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</guid>
      <description>This week was relatively quiet for me. But, here&amp;rsquo;s what I liked, mostly from my twitter timeline. If you follow me on twitter, there may not be anything new for you.
This short video on how Nima made it to Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious tournament made me cry each time I watched it. And movies/videos rarely make me cry.
Sacha Chua writes about her baby&amp;rsquo;s Microphthalmia and says this &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll make an awesome pirate. Or cyborg. Or cyborg pirate. If she wants.&amp;rdquo; Woah!
I discovered Rains Of Castamere by Krish Ashok and loved it. Some looping happened!
@varungrover wrote argued for using better insults than &amp;lsquo;Presstitue&amp;rsquo; and I agree. I have had similar thoughts on the other insults he talks about.
This tweet thread got me thinking about speaking up, and standing up, and how people fail to do it, and what could help prevent these failures.
This picture of kids praying at Haji Public School gave me hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-03</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed reading the full judgement given by the Madras High Court in the Perumal Murugan case. The court said something on the lines of: not all art may be for everyone, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t like a book, throw it away. The judgement also made it clear that it is the responsibility of the state to ensure that things don&amp;rsquo;t go haywire using appropriate measures, and banning things left, right and center is not the way to deal with it.
This letter that a Law professor wrote in response to a student&amp;rsquo;s complaint about him wearing a Black Lives Matter t-shirt is superb!
Gabriel Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s post with a list of mental models that he found repeatedly useful has been great. There have also been some great comments on it! I wish to keep going back to the post.
Anaghs shared a summary of Brian Christain&amp;rsquo;s Algorithms to Live By and the books seems really interesting. Added it to my reading list.
This ad by BigBazaar for Eid touched a chord.
Black Mirror&amp;rsquo;s The Entire History of You totally got to my head, and if you are interested in the future of technology and human behavior, I highly recommend watching this episode, if not all the episodes. Thanks to @9 for the recommendation.
Calvin and Hobbes&amp;rsquo; Search is a fun project - search for Christmas, Life and Universe and enjoy the wisdom!
Sowmya Rajendran&amp;rsquo;s post on how the menstrual cup touched her life more than anything else after the Internet, was an interesting read.
The lights in the audience truly look &amp;ldquo;amazingly beautiful&amp;rdquo; in this Coldplay video.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post things that made me happy or touched my heart, each week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-10</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</guid>
      <description>Airtel&amp;rsquo;s response to @karthikb351&amp;rsquo;s write up on how they are sniffing and censoring CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s traffic in India was funny but sad, though, not totally unexpected. For instance, see @kingslyj&amp;rsquo;s version of how this might end.
I loved this interview with Amanda Palmer where she talks about her stolen Ukulele, Music, her dad and her baby and her love for life comes across, like in everything else she does. &amp;lsquo;I want to get a couple of T-shirts printed for me and the baby that say: &amp;ldquo;We are determined to enjoy ourselves&amp;rdquo;&amp;lsquo;, she says.
A year old but inspiring article on Serena Williams, shared by @baali. I like how she says, she&amp;rsquo;s opening the next door for the next person, like the many people who opened many doors for her. @baali also recommended this song from Neerja as background music, and I loved it!
Pierre buttin&amp;rsquo;s screenshot art is amusing and gives a sense of how distracted he is, each day of the week, and how distracted we are, as a people.
We were walking through the fields and bushes in Hampi and stopped at the gate of a private property. A bearded man with a calm look on his face asked us &amp;ldquo;Do you know where you are headed?&amp;ldquo;. And then let us walk across his beautiful nature home to the other side, where we found this amusing sign.
Finally, this Nike India ad on Women in Sport is great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-17</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</guid>
      <description>@9 shared this story about Peter Norman. Woah, so inspirational!
This conversation with Amitav Ghosh on his latest book The Great Derangement is pretty scary! He says, &amp;ldquo;You know that this great derangement is ultimately going to lead to a great unraveling, but to see it working itself out, day after day, in the news, it&amp;rsquo;s so terrifying. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s here, it&amp;rsquo;s happening. You may not see it a direct connection between the events happening in the world today and the climate in general, but that relationship does exist. In Syria, everything started with a great drought. The Middle East, this entire Mediterranean region, is going through a historic drought. And if you think about how this tumult in the Arab world began, it was with protests over food in Tunisia. So what we&amp;rsquo;re facing really, if you like, is a catastrophic convergence of natural impacts and human impacts.&amp;rdquo; I ended up buying the book at Bookworm.
This IndiaSpend article on how quotas have helped the disadvantaged caste students is a really well written article, with informative charts.
Kenneth Reitz released Episode-2 of Import This, a podcast that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of and ended up listening to Episode-1. I really liked the discussion on being considerate to others in communities that you are part of. The quote that this episode ends with, &amp;ldquo;Software is all about the people. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss them. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss their experience.&amp;ldquo;, resonated well with me.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; how to be a wizard programmer sketch is rad! (tweet).
I watched the movie Blind Side (2009) with friends, and really liked it. SJ and Oher together, they are a blast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortful things</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/effortful-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/effortful-things/</guid>
      <description>That dense book you want to read but has been lying on your desk while you procrastinate on twitter. You know you&amp;rsquo;ll have to tune everything else out, and read slowly, word by word, trying to understand and make sense.
That vague blog post idea swirling in your head while you look at cat pictures, one after another. Distilling your thoughts and putting them down for general consumption is a lot of thinking and effort away.
That ${cool_programming_thing} that a talk got you excited about so long ago. But, watching talks and intending to start using it is all you do about it. You know its going to take a fair amount of reading, thinking and time, before you can really use it well.
Like all those squats and lifts you dread, these things are building your muscle. The thing about building muscle &amp;ndash; it needs effort and feels like so much hard work.
You can&amp;rsquo;t build muscles effortlessly. Go do those effortful things! Only if you care about those muscles, anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level-up Tools</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/level-up-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/level-up-tools/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to a friend I got an upgrade to our still-being-setup kitchen. I now have a non-stick pan along with a few more new additions. I would previously use a bowl that people usually use to boil milk etc. for making whatever I did. The non-stick pan feels so great! It has made it a lot simpler to make some of the things I used to, because its non-stick. And it has vastly expanded the possibilities of things I can make, by virtue of being flat and wide based. The pan is such a great addition to my kitchen paraphernalia, and it adds a new dimension to the kind of things I can make. I&amp;rsquo;m not here to write a user review for it, though.
What are such tools in other things that you do, that drastically changed the way you did something, or added a new dimension to the kinds of things you could do, tools that make you feel like you have a new super-power? Learning to write Python (after starting off with C) seemed to give me so much power allowing me to focus on the problem, rather than fussing over the low level details. Sasha mentions in this post how using a Spaced Repetition System like Anki drastically improved her efficiency because she could focus on thinking about higher level things rather than trying to recall or search for what method or function to use to do something.
What are some such level-up tools for you? Is there a systematic approach to discovering tools?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on &#34;5 Love Languages&#34;</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/5-love-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/5-love-languages/</guid>
      <description>I first heard of this book in a discussion on relationships amongst friends from RC. The discussion was quite interesting and the book received more than a couple of strong recommendations. So, I decided to pick it up.
Very simply, the book is codified common sense explaining what Love is. Gary Chapman, the author, started with the question &amp;ldquo;What makes you feel loved&amp;rdquo; and found that the answers could be grouped into the following 5 categories:
 Words of affirmation Quality time Receiving gifts Acts of service Physical touch,  which he calls the languages of love. He also proposes that people have a primary language of love, and a failure to speak to a person in their primary language would make them feel unloved.
The book is filled with anecdotes to explain what each of these languages means and how to speak them, along with practical advice and exercises to learn to speak each of these languages. Though the book has been written with couples in mind, the fundamental ideas in this book can be applied to any relationships. I feel like it has been helping me connect a few dots, ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve started reading it.
It has been totally worth my time to read this book. A highly recommended read!
Below are some of my notes. Feel free to suggest improvements (for readability and otherwise) on the notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning about Spaced Repetition, SuperMemo, Org-drill, et al.</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/learning-about-spaced-repetition-supermemo-org-drill-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/learning-about-spaced-repetition-supermemo-org-drill-et-al/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading a bunch of articles on the SuperMemo site (including the original thesis of P. A. Wozniack, the creator of SuperMemo). I initially started off trying to understand the algorithms SM2,5 and 8 which org-drill implements, but reading the articles has given me a lot of general background and theory on how memory works, and why SuperMemo is as effective as it is (for those who stick with it). This blog post is an attempt to summarize and capture what I have read in all those articles, and not get lost in them. I would recommend reading the thesis and the suggested reading there, yourself, but if you really don&amp;rsquo;t want to &amp;ndash; this blog post + the summary in here, and here would be a good alternative.
 Memory works by repetition. Each time you recall a fact, the time it takes for the memory to fade increases. Spaced repetition is the idea of repeating items, just when you are about to forget them &amp;ndash; trying to optimize the time spent on learning, as well as the retention of learned material.
 Prioritization of the items we need to learn is key to being able to stick to Spaced repetition. Beginners tend to be over-enthusiastic about the technique and fill up their system with stuff that they don&amp;rsquo;t really care about. Applicability of the knowledge you are trying to gain, is a good test for whether or not it goes into your system.
 Each version of SuperMemo comes with a slightly modified (on most occassions, improved!) algorithm. SM2, SM5, &amp;hellip; refer to these algorithms. Org-drill currently supports only sm2,5 and 8. It may be worth looking at sm15/16 and seeing if it can be implemented and is worth doing. In any case, using any of these is way better than not using Spaced repetition at all.
 Understanding what we are trying to learn goes a long way in helping memory. It is, therefore, good to start with basic material. People have been surprised by how easily the advanced stuff fell into place, once they had the basics covered.
 Keep items in the system simple. Stick to the minimum information principle. Keeping it simple, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you leave out on learning the complex stuff; instead break it into simpler components. Simpler items has the following advantages:
 Simple is easier to remember. Simpler items are easier to schedule. You get more resolution to figure out what the problem areas are. Simple makes brings in redundancy automatically. And redundancy is good for memory, just like it is for managing hardware failure.  Keep learning fun! Don&amp;rsquo;t make review sessions a chore. Think about the material you are reviewing. Edit/delete/improve items based on your reviews, then and there. Stay active.
 It is useful to add a link to the source of the items added to your system, considering that you wish to use the system over a long period of time (ideally, the rest of your life!)
 Prioritize, add examples, appeal to your emotional state, link to existing knowledge, use images. Anything else that works for you! Use all of these techniques, that work well and you probably already use in everyday life, in the items you add to your system, to make them easier to recall.
 Being physically fit and healthy is important for being so mentally. Exercise, sleep, eat well, avoid caffeine.
 Try incremental reading, as an input source of items into your memory system.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurse Center, 2014-06-25</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-06-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 09:51:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-06-25/</guid>
      <description> I like how some of the people here are taking check-ins so seriously. A bunch of people posted messages on Zulip, informing that they would not be able to make it to check-ins, and seemed quite sorry about it. Check-ins are indeed useful. At the end of every day, I review my work wondering what I did, and sometimes end up pushing myself harder, to have something reasonable to talk about during the check-ins! Yesterday, I read up about FFTs and ended up playing around with fft in scipy, and played around with audacity, etc. Nothing concrete, really. There was a &amp;ldquo;goals&amp;rdquo; workshop by Stacey, where she talked about how to get the most out of this batch of Hacker School, and then we split into groups of 3, and presented our goal-statements to each other, and gave our impressions of each others&amp;rsquo; goals. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a goal, but the exercise seemed to help, anyway. Also, I think it is making me nervous to treat Hacker School as super-important. It is important to make the best use of every hour, every minute here, but at the same time, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be constantly worrying about whether or not, whatever I&amp;rsquo;m doing is the best use of my time here. I think I would like to form some good habits, and make a few good friends, more than finish projects and build something uber-cool. Of course, it would be great to build awesome stuff (and may be the only reasonable way to form habits, and make friends) but I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about time running out. Never Graduate!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cold/</guid>
      <description>It was a pleasant Saturday evening in the middle of the winter. Christmas was just round the corner and love in the air. The sun was just setting and everything outside his window was given a fresh coat of snow, tickled by the red, quickly fading light. Not that he noticed. He stared blankly out of the window, looking at nothing in particular. He had just woken up from his afternoon nap; but he&amp;rsquo;d buy it if you told him he&amp;rsquo;d been sleeping for a year&amp;hellip;
You could see the icy river crawling ahead, from his window. People walking over the bridge, a few camera flashes going off, people stopping over and looking far ahead into the horizon &amp;ndash; collecting their thoughts, couples walking hand-in-hand enjoying each others&amp;rsquo; company; You could see it all, from up there! But, as they say, you only see what you look for. And he, couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any of this. His looked out of his window and saw none of this.
He is walking down the same bridge. He didn&amp;rsquo;t know where he was going; his head at least. His legs did; as always. He was walking down in his regular yellow shirt and black jeans, that you could mistake for a uniform, if you followed him for a few days. Extremely under-dressed for the chilly night, one would say. He kept walking down the main street, lined with shops brightly lit up for the festive season. The pavement bustled with with people walking with a spring in their step &amp;ndash; the spring that the festive season and all the love in the air brought to you. Not that he noticed it, or had any of it in his step.
Soon, he&amp;rsquo;s walking through the park. The park that was built to celebrate time, ticking away furiously. Or to celebrate the time everyone in the world had, to enjoy themselves. He walked past the skating rink, with lots of people having the time of their life, ice skating; and a lot more, awaiting their turn. The first timers, old and young, making up for their inexperience, with their excitement; holding onto whatever they can, to finish each round, to start the next! The veterans, taking the center-stage and showing off their moves! He was barely aware of their presence and just walked on, past all the action.
The music festival; he walked past it too, like the crowd didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, the noise didn&amp;rsquo;t, the music didn&amp;rsquo;t; like there was nothing happening! The fountain &amp;ldquo;felt&amp;rdquo; no different. The cold breeze, did sprinkle the water to quite a distance and everybody kept a safe distance to avoid the chilling shower, except for the kids, who found it amusing to run into the shower for a split second and run back madly. How could he walk just by it, and not feel a thing!
The lakefront. That is where his legs always brought him in the end. The brilliantly lit skyline was a delight to watch, but I don&amp;rsquo;t believe he saw any of it. He just stared into it, blankly. He kept staring, as the night got chillier and the surroundings kept getting more and more deserted. Seconds ticked away, minutes and hours passed by! He stayed on, staring ahead. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much below zero the mercury had gone. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first night he was spending staring into the nothingness. It turned out to be the coldest night, in a decade. But that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter to him. Nothing did. Nothing has, for a while now; Ever since he turned cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just one day</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/just-one-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/just-one-day/</guid>
      <description>The ripples on the quiet lake,
twinkling stars on a moonless night,
and his lonely, crazy, thoughts,
yet again, his faithful companions
on another of those countless nights,
searching for meaning, awaiting the dawn.
the night crawled by, as he drifted afloat,
memories of the past and dreams of the future,
until approaching footsteps, brought him back
did the chill of the wind, get to his head?
or was his guarded secret, not his anymore?
Before his thoughts, collect, he could,
his friend, from far away lands unknown,
was there with him, to share his thoughts,
to hear the wind hum the tunes of yore,
while the stars and the lake, as a duo, danced.
They watch the sun rise, from atop the hillock,
basking in the warmth, and see the town wake up,
lose themselves in the woods below,
on their way back, rest by the lake shore,
watching it, silently, shine in the daylight,
letting it wet their feet and clear his head.
Together, they cook themselves, a delicious meal,
n enjoy it, with some of the choicest old wine.
Catch-up on things, and yearn for more, discuss
all the many things, under the sun, and over,
without a clue, as to how much time flew by.
Riding away, as fast as they could, they reach,
just in time, as the sun set, over the seas,
perched on bicycles, in mirrored positions, with
resonating thoughts, the horizon, they watch
the sun set, the beach light up, and the fair begin.
They ate and drank, sung and danced and
just had a good time, for the rest of the night,
indulging, in all that the fair could offer.
the night was long, but if wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go on forever,
pretty well, they knew, they day was to end.
the twinkling stars they watched, yet again,
but to the sea&amp;rsquo;s song, on the still warm sand
slowly, but steadily, into sleep he drifted,
only to be awake, moments later, with the
bright sun coming harshly down upon him,
lighting up the lake, like a carpet of jewels.
all he had, once again, were just his thoughts,
the lake, and not the sea, by his side,
with fading impressions of an impossible dream
after all, wasn&amp;rsquo;t it just too much action,
for just one day, for a life engulfed by ennui?
One some day, he told himself, and walked away.
Inspired by a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand in Glove</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/hand-in-glove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/hand-in-glove/</guid>
      <description>the time, together spent,
the memories cherished,
all the love, concern and care
may they stay with us, for life.
as high and far as you like
may you fly, like you own the sky
while I fumble, with my flying guide
I see the world, through your eyes
may you run, with all your might
as if, fighting for life, you are.
struggling to walk, I stumble and fall,
but get up each time, inspired to run.
may you, in all that we shared
find strength to go on, if en-route
our paths diverged; you may have to wait,
but you shall see me, on the other side!
Thanks to Chaitu, I re-read Love Unvoiced a few times and realized, I was trying to say too much. Here&amp;rsquo;s another poem, with one part of what I wanted to say. I will not be writing newer poems, to say the other stuff. Perform your own Fourier analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Unvoiced</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/love-unvoiced/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/love-unvoiced/</guid>
      <description>Hard, I tried, to stay mum,
and keep it all within.
But, not much longer can I stand,
I give in, and here&amp;rsquo;s my song
wherever you are, anywhere you go,
whatever you do, or choose not to,
whatever you think and however you feel,
my love for you, it shall only grow.
Sweet, is the attachment,
but let it not keep you from flying.
the clear open sky, it&amp;rsquo;s all yours
fly! fly! fly!
see all that you want to,
and do all that you&amp;rsquo;d like to.
to your hearts content, fly!
without a care in the world, fly!
for, if ever, you wish to rest,
now you know, where to return
right here, I shall be,
with love, just a little more.
Mute, I chose to be, but, boy!
does it need to be told. All over me,
it&amp;rsquo;s written; and you, sure, read me!
Love you, for being the more loving one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who I am</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/who-i-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/who-i-am/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the body that dies
on missing a beat or one breath.
I&amp;rsquo;m not the mind, so fickle,
I&amp;rsquo;m in heaven one moment, and next in hell.
I&amp;rsquo;m the moments I live,
not the ones, in which I just exist.
I&amp;rsquo;m the dreams I dream,
those fulfilled, and not just yet.
I am the occasions I grace
and those, missed, where I am.
I am the words I spoke,
those I wrote, and those I will.
I am all that I create,
and the stuff that I catalyse.
I am the love I receive,
and all of it that I spread.
Don&amp;rsquo;t cry, when I die,
for I never really will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just another bunch</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/just-another-bunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/just-another-bunch/</guid>
      <description>Come spring -
a fresh lease of green
drapes the bare branches.
The leaves, dancing and whistling
to the tunes of the wind
playing, screaming, and singing,
in each other&amp;rsquo;s company, enjoying.
Singing to one another
promises of sticking together,
come what may, through it all.
The song goes on,
but the count goes down,
not noticed or just unacknowledged,
first by one and then by many more.
the song, still, goes on.
And the promises too, of course.
The song goes on and on and on.
Until silence falls upon, when all
of them are gone. The tree, knowing well,
watches on - it won&amp;rsquo;t be long before
a new bunch springs up to sing the song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good, Bad or Human?</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/good-bad-or-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/good-bad-or-human/</guid>
      <description>Well, this could be called a post after ages, considering that most of previous posts have just been &amp;lsquo;news reports&amp;rsquo;. I have been wanting to make a post since long, but I probably lost it. I really am unable to write anything that I find worth posting [It does raise questions about the existence of this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, to answer that question to myself.]
This post is provoked by an act of sharing, an act of kindness, an act of goodness, that surprised me. This post isn&amp;rsquo;t about the act itself, but it&amp;rsquo;s about me being surprised. Why on earth should I (or anybody) be surprised, when someone is just being human? Aren&amp;rsquo;t human beings meant to be and feel human?
I wonder why people say, &amp;ldquo;this is a bad, bad world.&amp;rdquo; I find a lot of goodness and humanness around me. Unless I strain my memory really hard, I can only recall people who try to be as good and nice as they can be; People trying to be as human as possible. Either there&amp;rsquo;s something utterly wrong with my judgment of people or there&amp;rsquo;s something wrong with the general feeling that the world is a bad, bad place.
There&amp;rsquo;s one other possibility that just strikes me - I am so nice to people that, everyone else tries to be nice with me. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am such a big deviation from the average. I&amp;rsquo;m just another goat, in the great herd.
And another one, I&amp;rsquo;m in a really special place, presently. I have been only to the special places. I have visited only the places that are at an extreme, far away from the &amp;lsquo;average&amp;rsquo; place in the world. But, given I&amp;rsquo;m just another goat in the great herd, this is very unlikely. I am probably grazing at a random spot on the great grasslands.
Since these are ruled out, it boils down to either a wrong judgment or a wrong general feeling.
Coming to my judgment, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an Oracle or the wise one, but I&amp;rsquo;m no dumb ass either. Well, taking the statistical route, the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve had any real &amp;ldquo;nasty&amp;rdquo; surprises in dealing with people has been much lesser than the number of times things turned out nearly as expected. My judgment could, therefore, possibly given some credibility.
So, that leaves me with just one possibility. The idea that the world is a bad, bad place is not entirely true, if not completely absurd and outright wrong. The world is really a nice place, with &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; beings inhabiting it. The nasty surprises that you get, really are the surprises and not the general rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To do or not to do</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/to-do-or-not-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/to-do-or-not-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Achieve something, I&amp;rsquo;m often reminded,
achieve something, something that&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile.
Don&amp;rsquo;t just kill time, they say,
for, brutally, it shall kill you someday.
Make the best use of time, I tell myself,
for I realize, how I spend my days
is how I&amp;rsquo;m spending my life and
I&amp;rsquo;m going to get just one of it!
But, what is worthwhile, I wonder
everything seems so good one moment
and all meaning vanishes the very next.
I&amp;rsquo;m utterly confused, somebody help!
Pick one from, spoke my brother,
the &amp;lsquo;everything&amp;rsquo; that seems good
and do it right, just, do it right!
Life, as you live through it, shall
teach you to do things that are right
and at the end of it all, you&amp;rsquo;ll
never regret what you&amp;rsquo;ve done
but, only what you couldn&amp;rsquo;t!
Inspired by
 a late-night conversation with a friend Annie Dillard, &amp;ldquo;How we spend our days is, of course, how we spend our lives&amp;rdquo;  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>