<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:55:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling from Manali to Leh - An FAQ</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cycling-from-manali-to-leh-an-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/cycling-from-manali-to-leh-an-faq/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  So, you cycled from Manali to Leh? Who is &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;? How did you decide to do this? What is the maximum elevation you cycled to? How long did the whole ride take? Was it really hard? Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t you finish the ride? So, you do really need a support vehicle? How much did the support vehicle cost you? Did you carry your own bikes? Did the flights charge you for the bikes? Would you recommend me to carry my bike? What cycle spares/tools did you carry? What sort of preparation did you do for this ride? Can you share your ride plan? What was a typical day during the trip, like? What was the most enjoyable part of the ride? What was the most challenging part of the ride? You keep saying it was cold, how cold was it really? Did you meet any interesting people en-route? Would you do this again? If yes, which part of the year would you do it? If not, what other routes would you try? Do you have any pictures that you can share?  So, you cycled from Manali to Leh? Well, Not really. We cycled from Kalath to Whiskey Nala &amp;ndash; a distance of 280km &amp;ndash; which is about 60% of the Manali-Leh route.
Who is &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;? Vivek and I were on the bikes. Shabu was our guide helping us fix our bikes and fixing up our meals, but more than anything else, ensuring that we don&amp;rsquo;t freeze to death. Susheel was driving along and cheering us.
How did you decide to do this? Vivek and I were going to Coorg with Prats and Addy, and Prats told us a whole lot of stories of her adventures in the mountains. Not sure how bicycles came into the picture, but as soon as they did, both of us got really excited about it. This was on some sort of a bucket list for me, ever since I read Vatsap&amp;rsquo;s cycling story many years ago. Soon, after we were back in town, the ball was set rolling&amp;hellip;
What is the maximum elevation you cycled to? We started off at around 1.8km and went up to about 5km in a span of 5 days. We also spent a day in Manali, getting our cycles fixed and acclimatizing. You can see the elevation profile here.
How long did the whole ride take? Our plan was to finish the whole distance in 7 days. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get to our designated camp on the 5th day, and had to use the support car to get to camp before it got dark. We decided to end the ride once we took our bikes off the road.
Was it really hard? Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t you finish the ride? We expected the primary challenges to be:
 the altitude and lack of oxygen the fatigue from riding day after day after day&amp;hellip;  But, cold played a much bigger role than we thought it would. As we got higher and higher, it got so cold that we spent a significant amount of energy and brain cycles on trying to fight the cold, rather than enjoying the views or pushing ourselves to keep going despite the non-cold-related discomfort.
So, you do really need a support vehicle? Not really, if you were riding in better weather or were better prepared. The Manali to Leh route usually has a lot of temporary shops setup during the season, where you could crash, if it was too cold to just crash in your tent. Since, we were going after the season had almost ended, many of these shops were no longer open, and having the support car turned out to be quite useful on the last day.
How much did the support vehicle cost you? It turned out to be quite an expense for something we originally didn&amp;rsquo;t have in mind. We spent about 20k on the vehicle, fuel and the driver&amp;rsquo;s fee. We also paid our guide + cook + bicycle expert, separately.
Did you carry your own bikes? Yes.
 Flew from Bengaluru to Delhi Took a bus from Delhi to Manali Carried the bikes on the support car from Whiskey Nala to Leh Flew back from Leh to Delhi  Did the flights charge you for the bikes? The carrier (IndiGo) from BLR to DEL charged us a handling fees of Rs. 1000. The carrier (Vistara) on the return journey didn&amp;rsquo;t.
Would you recommend me to carry my bike? You could find bikes on rent, both in Manali and Leh, for about 500 to 700 per day. It would cost about 5-7k, based on how you plan your ride, to rent a bike. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to make arrangements to get the bike returned back to the place you rent it from &amp;ndash; this can get a little tricky.
If you already own a bike, and can it packed in a proper box, I would highly recommend that. The derailleurs, the shifters, and other such moving parts need to be well packed and guarded. Use a box or a cycling bag to put it in. Get professional help from a cycle retailer nearby, if required. This is one thing you cannot take any chances on, or your whole trip may be jeopardized!
We hadn&amp;rsquo;t paid enough attention to packing our bikes, and one of our bikes took quite some beating on the way to Delhi. On the way back, we managed to get the bike packed in a box and it was a breeze.
What cycle spares/tools did you carry? We were sort of ill prepared in this department. We only had the following:
 Hand pump Puncture kit Spare tubes (2 nos.) Allen key set  Based on advice from Shabu, I think you should also take these things:
 Brake cables Gear cables Spare tyre (1 Nos.) Brake shoes/pads Few spokes Chain oil  What sort of preparation did you do for this ride? We did a handful of 50-100km rides on weekends before this one. The only real elevation training/trial that we did was the Kalhatti climb, one weekend before this ride. This turned out to be pretty useful, and we found all the other climbs during this ride much less steeper than some of the Kalhatti ones.
Can you share your ride plan? What we actually rode    Day Start End Distance Elevation gain Comments     0 Kalath - -  Fix cycles and acclimatize   1 Kalath Marhi 45km 1675m Prepare to cross Rohtang!   2 Marhi Keylong 80km -210m Crossed Rohtang (3970m)   3 Keylong Patseo 48km +644m Easy ride; Deepak Tal!   4 Patseo Sarchu 64km +522m Crossed Baralachala(4902m)!   5 Sarchu Whiskey Nala 48km +465m Gata loops &amp;amp; Nakeela(4924m)    Original plan    Day Start End Distance Elevation gain Comments     5 Sarchu Pang 73km +225m Gata-loops, Nakeela(4924m) &amp;amp; Lachung La(5065m)   6 Pang Lato 103km -530m Moore Plains, Tanglang La (5328m)   7 Lato Leh 70km -600m Lots of downhill!    What was a typical day during the trip, like?  Wake up between 7 and 8, depending on when you can see/feel the warm sun. Laze in bed if you woke up too early, and the sun hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet warmed the place up. Eat porridge, and a few slices of bread with peanut butter. Pack ourselves up in as many layers of clothing as we can, while still being able to pedal. Check the bikes for any loose/fallen-off/broken parts, blow, etc. Start pedaling away - usually between 9 and 10. It&amp;rsquo;s too cold to start earlier. Keep adjusting the clothing, based on how cold/warm it is, and the wind chill. Keep munching, or sipping on some water (plain or mixed with some energizer). Continue pedaling, and start looking at the milestones a little more carefully. Lunch is on our mind, already. Lunch at around 1:30pm - usually, a couple of boiled eggs, and a potato. May be a chocolate, and some Frooti. More pedaling. The kilometers start getting harder, the chill is getting harsher. Huff and puff, and reach our camp for the day. Hi-fives! We&amp;rsquo;d try and reach the camp while there is still some sunlight there to keep us warm. Stretch it out, and switch into dry, warm clothes. Grab a quick snack - whole packets of biscuits would just disappear, alongside some tea. Talk, walk around, ponder about life, think about the day that&amp;rsquo;s been, think about the day that is to come, and all that jazz. Eat dinner - dal and rice, mostly. Sleep like logs. Unless, there&amp;rsquo;s a rat in the room that&amp;rsquo;s attacking our dry fruits.  What was the most enjoyable part of the ride?  I really enjoyed sitting at Deepak Tal, and just looking at the clear water The climb to Baralacha La was the most challenging part of the ride. We could see that the weather was really bad in all the peaks around us, and it was getting really cold. Briefly, it was even snowing very lightly and we could see tiny snow flakes floating in front of us. The feeling of reaching the top of passes was quite thrilling, for both Rohtang and Baralacha La. Nakee La, not so much, since we still had about 30km ahead of us to finish the day. It was humbling to see all the BRO folks working to keep the roads open and functional! A big salute to them! Each time we had a truck or some bikers pass by, we would wave at them or show thumbs up, and it would give us some additional energy to keep pushing ahead. The tree covered road in Sissu was just mind blowingly beautiful, with all the trees golden and yellow, preparing for the fall. It was also nice to turn 30, in the hills. Vivek tried to make it as special, for me, as he could.  What was the most challenging part of the ride? The cold. (See, the answer on why we didn&amp;rsquo;t finish the ride).
You keep saying it was cold, how cold was it really? On the night we camped at Sarchu, the water in our bottles and unwashed cups had frozen. We had gone to sub zero temperatures on many nights, it looks like. The winds during the day were quite chilly, and got worse as we gained altitude.
Did you meet any interesting people en-route?  We met a guy from Slovenia who has been taking a couple or so months off for the past 10 years. He was riding around with a 55kg weighing bike for the past 3 weeks, and was going from Leh to Manali, when we met him. He had a lot of stories to tell &amp;ndash; including recommending that we go cycling in Iceland, and enjoy watching the Northern lights from hot water baths.
 Shabu himself had a lot of stories to tell about all the people he had taken on this ride - from guys with a $6k bike to a 70 year old doing the route his 4th time to the guy who would eat only olive oil mixed in rice to safeguard his tummy, and more!
 All the aachos and aamas in the shops/guest houses/etc that we went to were really nice to us. Most of the folks in the shops were planning to leave in a few days after we had met them since it had gotten really cold.
 We had our camp-site at Marhi in the compound of a HP state guest house. The care taker walks up to us, while we are setting up the tent, and says, &amp;ldquo;Idhar kahi par bhi baithna mana hai, 10 hazaar ka fine lag jaayega. Udhar toilet bana hua hai&amp;rdquo;, pointing to the public toilets in a distance, &amp;ldquo;paisa nahi lagega&amp;rdquo;. We had a good laugh, and ended up wondering if it was Swach Bharat showing some effect.
  We probably would&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot more people, and met a lot more interesting people, if we were there in better weather and didn&amp;rsquo;t have a support vehicle taking care of us. Next time!
Would you do this again? May be. We feel like we got a taste of the challenge of the ride, and the rest of the route wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be anymore challenging than what we already saw, if we did it in better weather. But, the better weather would also mean more traffic and noise on the road.
If yes, which part of the year would you do it? Late August to mid-September might be a better time. We&amp;rsquo;d also need to look out for rains and land-slides, though.
If not, what other routes would you try?  Cycling around Europe sounds like a fun thing to try Rides in the western ghats and/or Kerala seem promising A Tour of Meghalaya was something a friend suggested Pushing that a little more, ride all the way to Singapore/Indonesia, starting at home  Do you have any pictures that you can share? A post shared by Punch (@punchagan) on Nov 6, 2017 at 2:44am PST
  You can find some pictures and videos here. The album also includes some pictures from our practice rides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HT interactives</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/ht-interactives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/ht-interactives/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the interactives by HindustanTimes, and thoroughly loved some of them. It felt like a fresh breath of air amongst all the other Indian data driven journalism that I have been coming across in the recent past.
The visualizations are a lot more interactive than some of the other Indian publications. These remind me of NYT&amp;rsquo;s interactives, which are amongst the best you&amp;rsquo;d see, while more often than not exploring data in the Indian context. I really like that they explore a variety of ways of doing these visualizations, and don&amp;rsquo;t just fit the data into one of the many standard options available in a visualization library.
It feels like they are willing to take their time to do these visualizations, and are willing to collect data from multiple sources, and combine multiple datasets to tell a story. I also like the fact that the visualizations and the articles are more open-ended, allowing users to interact with and explore the data, rather than trying to come up with an article full of conclusions with a click-baity title. The fact that one of the sections is called Just for Fun speaks to me.
The data and the code used in most of these interactives is open and available on GitHub, which is nice!
On the whole, I think they are doing pretty good work, and I shall be on the lookout for even better stuff from them. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up a thing or two from their work, in my projects. Hopefully, other teams doing similar work will also learn from there and produce more good stuff for greedy readers like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prime Ministers of India - Simple d3 timeline</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/prime-ministers-of-india-simple-d3-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 21:25:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/prime-ministers-of-india-simple-d3-timeline/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on a simple time-line showing the terms of Prime Ministers of India. Currently, the time-line is not very useful and only shows the duration of the term in the time0line, with some pictures, with the hover tool-tip linking to a Wikipedia page. The interactive version is here.
A simple extension of this would be to add historical events of different types over this time-line, with links to more information on these events. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure, where I&amp;rsquo;m going with this, though.
Any ideas and suggestions are more than welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs frame as a pop-up input</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/emacs-frame-as-a-pop-up-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 22:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/emacs-frame-as-a-pop-up-input/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try using a dialog box/pop-up window as a prompt to remind me to periodically make journal entries. I had the following requirements:
 Simple, light-weight dialog box that allows text of arbitrary length Ability to launch the dialog from the shell Ability to have some placeholder or template text, each time the dialog is shown Save the input text to a specific org-mode file Write as little code of my own, as possible, to do this  I had initially thought about using a tool like zenity, or write a simple dialog box in Python using Qt, wx or even tk, and then yank the input text at the desired location. This probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have turned out to be too hard, but getting things to look and work exactly the way I wanted would have required more code than I was willing to write or maintain.
After avoiding doing this for a while, I finally realized that I could simply use Emacs with a new frame with the appropriate dimensions, and with the correct file/buffer open to the desired location. This would
 eliminate the need for me to write the UI myself eliminate the need to do text manipulation in code, to yank it at the right place, in the right form. By directly opening up the editor at the required location, the onus is on me (as a text inputting user) to put it in, the way I want it. additionally provide me the comfort of being able to write with the full power of Emacs - keybindings and all that jazz. let me leverage elisp to do essentially whatever I want with the buffer being displayed as the dialog box.  I ended up with a command that looks something like this
emacsclient -c -n\ -F &#39;((title . &amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;) (left . (+ 550)) (top . (+ 400)) (width . 110) (height . 12))&#39;\ -e &#39;(pc/open-journal-buffer)&#39;   This worked pretty nicely, except for the fact that with gnome-shell, the pop-up frame doesn&amp;rsquo;t always appear raised. It often gets hidden in the Emacs windows group, and the whole idea of the pop-up acting as a reminder goes for a toss! But, thanks to this Ask Ubuntu post, I could fix this pretty easily.
emacsclient -c -n\ -F &#39;((title . &amp;quot;Title&amp;quot;) (left . (+ 550)) (top . (+ 400)) (width . 110) (height . 12))&#39;\ -e &#39;(progn (pc/open-journal-buffer) (raise-frame) (x-focus-frame (selected-frame)))&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog trends from word clouds</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/blog-trends-from-word-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 22:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/blog-trends-from-word-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I came across a couple of fun word clouds, and felt like generating a word cloud for my blog content to get a sense of the major themes on my blog, over the years.
With some simple Python code, I was able to parse the blog and get the word frequency over the years. I then used a modified version of this d3 example to generate a word cloud.
Using all the words used in each year to generate the word-cloud, made it very noisy. So, I switched to using only the top 50 words for each year.
 The word cloud doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem very useful or insightful, but was fun to generate. Each year&amp;rsquo;s cloud seems to have some words that gives me a sense of some major events/themes for that year, though it may not be very apparent to anybody other than me.
The years which have a lot of posts have clear winners, but the winning words are quite generic. For example, 2007 has words like &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo;, etc., as winners. To try to get rid of the generic words in the word cloud, I tried a quick and dirty tf-idf based word-cloud, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t really seem to help.
 I might get back to this later, to try and improve the tf=idf word cloud. There are also other problems, like code-blocks in posts contributing variable names, urls contributing domain names, etc.
Also, a simple line chart of the usage of tags vs. year might give a better sense of the themes in the blog by year, even though it may not look as fancy as a word-cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 years of floods in India</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/30-years-of-floods-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 19:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/30-years-of-floods-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this post showing the major flooding events in the US, I created a similar graphic for India. You can find an interactive version here &amp;ndash; hovering over each flooding, shows some more information about the event.
 The graphic uses flooding related data from the Dartmouth Flood Observatory The data for 2017 events is not up-to date. It is very likely that there is some missing data, and some inaccuracies in the data. 1987, for instance, doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the Bihar flood. The flood severity is indicated by the color of each shape Each shape represents the geographic flood extents - based on information obtained from news sources. The data for India map shape is obtained from this topojson collection  It is interesting to look at the severity definitions here &amp;ndash; the extreme class floods, for instance, are defined to be those that have an estimated recurrence interval of over 100 years. In a span of 30 odd years, there are a whole bunch of regions which have been affected by extreme floods. Yet another case in point showing that the climate change shit has really hit the roof!
Code I used ogr2ogr to convert the shape file obtained from the Dartmouth Flood Observatory
ogr2ogr -f geoJSON data/floods.json FloodArchive_region.shp  This file turned out to be about 6MB. I created a file with only Indian floods by parsing the json file.
import json with open(&#39;floods.json&#39;, encoding=&#39;latin-1&#39;) as f: data = json.load(f) india_features = [ feature for feature in data[&#39;features&#39;] if feature[&#39;properties&#39;][&#39;COUNTRY&#39;] == &#39;India&#39; ] data[&#39;features&#39;] = india_features # FIX some names in the data NAME_FIXES = [ (&#39;Tropical Storm K&#39;, &#39;Tropical Storm Komen&#39;), (&#39;Tropical Storm Hudhug&#39;, &#39;Tropical Storm Hudhud&#39;), ] for feature in india_features: for name, fix in NAME_FIXES: cause = feature[&#39;properties&#39;][&#39;MAINCAUSE&#39;] if name in cause: feature[&#39;properties&#39;][&#39;MAINCAUSE&#39;] = cause.replace(name, fix) with open(&#39;india-floods.json&#39;, &#39;w&#39;, encoding=&#39;latin-1&#39;) as f: json.dump(data, f)  The visualization code itself is about a hundred odd lines of d3 code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back, Hopefully</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/back-hopefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 22:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/back-hopefully/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything here for almost a year. I needed to break the silence. So, here we go with a not-so-useful post showing how frequently I have been posting to this blog, to get a sense of how long this break has been in comparison to other silences in the past.
Neither the code below, nor the plots are very insightful. But, I just hope this will get me started on the path to blogging more regularly. See you around!
Parsed post content I wrote some code to parse the content of the blog, and each post object looks something like this:
{&#39;date&#39;: datetime.datetime(2010, 3, 17, 18, 30, tzinfo=&amp;lt;UTC&amp;gt;), &#39;draft&#39;: False, &#39;tags&#39;: [&#39;blab&#39;, &#39;life&#39;, &#39;poem&#39;], &#39;title&#39;: &#39;Just another bunch&#39;} Post count: 190  Post frequency by year import pandas posts = pandas.DataFrame(posts) counts = posts[&#39;date&#39;].groupby(posts[&#39;date&#39;].dt.year).count() plot = counts.plot(kind=&#39;bar&#39;, figsize=(8, 6)) plot.set_xlabel(&#39;Years&#39;) plot.set_ylabel(&#39;# of posts&#39;)   Post frequency by month # Add a DatetimeIndex to the Dataframe posts.index = pandas.DatetimeIndex(posts[&#39;date&#39;].values) counts = posts[&#39;date&#39;].groupby(pandas.TimeGrouper(&#39;M&#39;)).count() ax = counts.plot(kind=&#39;bar&#39;, figsize=(12, 8)) n = 5 ticks = ax.xaxis.get_ticklocs() labels = counts.index.strftime(&#39;%Y-%m&#39;) labels = ax.xaxis.set_ticklabels(labels[::n]) ticks = ax.xaxis.set_ticks(ticks[::n]) ax.set_xlabel(&#39;year-month&#39;) ax.set_ylabel(&#39;# of posts&#39;)   Work-flow I jumped onto the hugo bandwagon too.
I was totally impressed by how fast it is, and have been meaning to try it out for a while, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed with the built-in org-mode support it came with. This changed when I finally came across the ox-hugo package that does a wonderful job of exporting blog posts from an org file to hugo&amp;rsquo;s markdown format. I have contributed a couple of patches to it, to make it work better for myself and hopefully for others too.
Also, for this post, I used ob-ipython with the enhancements from scimax and it has really made the whole experience quite enjoyable.
Among other things, I think one of the reasons for those peaks in the second half of 2010, was having a smooth work-flow. My current work-flow feels pretty nice too, and I hope it&amp;rsquo;ll reduce some of the friction in writing more posts.
Onwards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-09-04</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</guid>
      <description>This week was a busy one, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really consume too much web content.
A colleague mentioned that he was reading the book &amp;ndash; The Millennial Project: Colonizing the Galaxy in Eight Easy Steps and it seemed to have some interesting ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across before.
The Berklee Indian Ensemble performed at the Bengaluru Ganesh Utsava and I went along with Sunil to their performance, which we thoroughly loved.
I liked some of Chet Baker instrumentals that I listened to this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-28</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</guid>
      <description>I liked this article advising developers on having healthy relationships. Most of it is common sense stuff &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Whether it be a side project or main project, understand that sacrificing relationships isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it.&amp;rdquo;
I really enjoyed this article by Priyanka on how she started talking to Auto Drivers. She shares a bunch of stories of drivers she talked to, that makes me wonder how many more such stories just go unheard, because I don&amp;rsquo;t talk.
@scopatz wrote up a nice argument explaining why @github should add back BSD to the list of licenses shown on the site. It taught me a thing or two about BSD and MIT.
I enjoyed spending the weekend at @mavin&amp;rsquo;s place, discussing continuous improvement in life, among other things. Also, had a lot of fun playing Psyche. The game is so addictive, but the app is not all that great. Someone should make a more robust app for this, or something that piggybacks on an existing network service like Telegram or Facebook chat or Google hangouts.
Falling In Love At A Coffee Shop by Landon Pigg is a lovely song, that I discovered this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-21</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</guid>
      <description>Vox has a nice short video on shutting up about the y-axis &amp;ndash; It&amp;rsquo;s long past time to say no to y-axis fundamentalism, they say.
The New York Times has a great visual history of which countries have dominated the Summer Olympics.
This story of Dipa by ESPN is an inspirational read.
An old post on a Frameless Geodesic Dome that Bruce Hauman (of Figwheel fame) built himself is very cool!
This article on India&amp;rsquo;s Gozoomo shutting down shop and returning VC money is heartening and gives me some hope about startups in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Public Jupyter Server, quickly!</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/create-a-public-jupyter-server-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/create-a-public-jupyter-server-quickly/</guid>
      <description>I create public Jupyter notebooks once in a while, to collaborate with a friend, or to make it easier for myself to work with data on a remote machine.
Each time I need to look up the docs, and manually set-up a few things, before I can start using the notebook.
I just wrote a bash script that does the following, quickly -
 Install Jupyter into a temporary virtualenv Create certificate files Start the server with https enabled and a password Delete all temporary files, when the server is shutdown   You can get it here, if you&amp;rsquo;d like to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-14</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</guid>
      <description>NYTimes has been doing some amazing visualizations for the Olympics and this time lapse visualization of Bolt&amp;rsquo;s 100m Gold is great!
The History Project produced a book called Partitioned Histories that tries to contrast the narratives of India and Pakistan on their histories using school history text books. What a great idea!
This video about the Sunshine Orchestra being trained and tutored by Rahman and his KM Music Conservatory is touching.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; posts on how to decide and think about what to work on are great. &amp;ldquo;Even reliably recognizing good ideas is hard!&amp;rdquo;, she says, and this resonates with me. Writing a release email as a way to think about why you are doing something is great!
Jasdev wrote about his monthly check-ins with friends. I thought they were such a great idea - simple, yet, powerful. &amp;ldquo;The only regret I have about these checkins is not starting sooner.&amp;ldquo;, he writes.
This Vox article on America&amp;rsquo;s increasing wealth gap along racial lines is really well done and thought provoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Trends, Clickbaits, and PV Sindhu</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/google-trends-clickbaits-and-pv-sindhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/google-trends-clickbaits-and-pv-sindhu/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR
 Am I saying India doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a caste problem?
No, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a HUGE problem!
 Are these articles on Google Trends and Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste useful at all?
Just more click-baits and no useful contribution to the discussion on caste.
  First of all, congratulations to PV Sindhu on making it to the finals and giving the world number one a hard fight!
This post, though, is not a celebratory one. I read this article &amp;ndash; While PV Sindhu fought hard for a medal, many Indians googled her caste &amp;ndash; by the News Minute thanks to a re-tweet by TM Krishna. I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have paid much attention to it, if not for the retweet by TMK.
Caste is a huge problem for the country, and if you still like to pretend it isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; read this for a start. I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that some people searched for Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste while she was battling it out at Rio. But, some people also searched for Badminton rules, and others for Sania Mirza! What surprises me is that the article doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to put the data in a context at all. Nor do I understand the contribution this article makes to the discussion on caste.
 I played around a little more with these search terms and Google Trends, and here are a few things that I thought were worth sharing.
Indian trends First of all, the article says &amp;ldquo;Many Indians&amp;rdquo;, and gives off cumulative month-wise numbers (UPDATE [2016-08-21 Sun 12:15]: which are so wrong! See Sankrant Sanu&amp;rsquo;s excellent article on India Facts). But, what does it really mean?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if anybody actually wrote about how many people actually followed the match, but Sindhu actually managed to get a whole lot of people interested!
 More people searched for PV Sindhu than the daily average number of searches (not hits) for Facebook and very close to the daily number of searches for Porn &amp;ndash; two of the biggest things Internet is allegedly used for. Can you see the red line at the bottom? That is the number of people who actually searched for Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste &amp;ndash; a tiny blip.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look. Here&amp;rsquo;s a plot of some of the other auto suggest terms + badminton rules &amp;amp; courts compared to Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s name.
 Nothing other than badminton rules (which is at about 1% of max. searches) is even visible, clearly.
So, these other terms (wiki &amp;amp; caste being auto-suggested ones) are nowhere near the actual number of searches being made for PV Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s name alone.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of the name graph to get a closer look at the other terms.
  The maximum number of people searching for Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste is at about a fifth of the maximum number of people searching for badminton rules. Interpreting it is upto you. But, I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised knowing how significant caste has been in our society. Also, notice that searches for wiki and caste fall off more gradually than the searches for the rules which peak while the game is being played and watched.
 Unsurprisingly, a bulk of the searches appear to be coming from Andhra and Telangana. Notice that the other states are searching more for the rules or her wiki page.
    Do you notice that the red (caste), blue (wiki) and violet (images) lines following a similar trend, until the last few hours? What do you think is happening there? It&amp;rsquo;s the shitty click baits working! Look at the trends from ~8:30AM to ~12:30AM below &amp;ndash; the red has spread to other states as well!    And this is how it looks by the evening (17:00-21:00). Well done, folks! The click bait articles totally succeeded!   If you are wondering how much effect the auto suggestions are having in suggesting people to try searching for caste, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that is much because wiki and images are the other auto-suggest terms, with no such surges in the number of searches.
Trends from the Telugu states We could see that the two Telugu states were more worried about the caste, than the rest of the country. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how abnormal they are.
  You can definitely see the red line more prominently. In case of Andhra the peak searches for caste are at about 5% of the name searches. A statistically significant difference from the rest of the country.
Let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in at the auto-suggest terms alone.
  Woah, Andhra is definitely quite an aberration from the rest of the country. From about 1/5th of the maximum number of searches for rules, the maximum number of caste searches jumps to about twice. Telangana also is different, but much less so.
Tamil Nadu&amp;rsquo;s trends below for comparison. You can&amp;rsquo;t help noticing the last few hours, can you?
 NOTE: The trends and screen-shots for the states are slightly more recent than the others.
Conclusion Without a context, I don&amp;rsquo;t really see the point of these &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; articles. It seems more click-bait-y than useful to me.
If you still feel many Indians were searching for Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste, while she was fighting it out, go ahead and play with Google trends here. Add/remove terms, change the time and location filters. Some terms that could be interesting to add to the comparison are: Kashmir, Independence day, Facebook.
Later, I looked at the search results and then found that this article wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one like it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to read the others, but I really hope at least some of them are talking sense. Is any of them really trying to contribute to the discussion on caste, meaningfully?
Also, the actual search results don&amp;rsquo;t seem to give useful answers to the folks so curious about Sindhu&amp;rsquo;s caste. I hope none of these articles are trying to help them out.
Finally, if you are using Google Trends to write an article, Danny Page has some really good advice.
Thanks to Kamal, baali and 9 for reading and reviewing drafts of this. Errors mine, obviously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-07</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</guid>
      <description>Great visualizations about how global temperatures have been changing in the last ~165 years. If you are still a global warming skeptic, you definitely must see them.
These visualizations of Michael Phelps&amp;rsquo; performances at Olympics over the years by NYTimes are great, too!
I came across these delightful videos (1, 2) of girls and boys playing cricket at Haji Public School. Look ma, no sexism in coverage of sports.
This (Telugu) interview of Dr Jayaprakash Narayan is truly inspiring. Also, YouTube recommended his conversation with Sadhguru Jaggi Vasudev, which was unexpectedly insightful, and covers a wide variety of topics &amp;ndash; spirituality, religion, social organizations, politics, socialism vs. capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-31</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Lots of Olympics stuff this week!
I really liked this ad - Rukna Nahi Hai - wishing all the Olympians a wonderfully spirited competition, at Rio. Go!
Brazilian marathoner Vanderlei Cordeiro de Lima, the man who lit the Olympic flame, inspires me with his spirit.
This story of Mohan Kumar from Ambattur, a Chennai suburb is inspiring. &amp;ldquo;Now I am on the relay team. But in the next Olympics, I want to qualify for the individual event. That&amp;rsquo;s my aim.&amp;ldquo;, he says.
@vandith recommended the Nike+ Training App to me and I really like it. They have some amazing workouts and pretty neat personalized workout plans.
Coke Studio Pakistan is trying a delightful experiment with their show this time &amp;ndash; they are trying to use lights and vibrations to let the hearing-impaired experience the music on their show better!
Sainath&amp;rsquo;s keynote at Film Writers Association conference was yet another of his thought-provoking speeches. He sends you down a spiral of thought, when he says, &amp;ldquo;How agonised we are when people die, and how untroubled we are by how they live&amp;rdquo;. I also enjoyed watching his (long) casual chat from an year ago, talking about his life and influences on him.
David Sassoon the founder of InsideClimate News writes about Non-Profit journalism, the need for it, and how to have more of it. He writes about it in the American context, but India has its own share of troubles. I consume quite a bit of news from independent sources, but don&amp;rsquo;t really contribute to keep them going. I should turn this around.
A bunch of residents of Urur Olcott Kuppam in Chennai responded to media&amp;rsquo;s broken coverage of TM Krishna&amp;rsquo;s Magsaysay award. I really liked how assertive they were about their role in the music festival, its role in their lives, and in clarifying how they see their fishing village as opposed to how the media portrayed it. They don&amp;rsquo;t mince any words.
You can find my older weekly posts like this here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-24</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</guid>
      <description>This week was relatively quiet for me. But, here&amp;rsquo;s what I liked, mostly from my twitter timeline. If you follow me on twitter, there may not be anything new for you.
This short video on how Nima made it to Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious tournament made me cry each time I watched it. And movies/videos rarely make me cry.
Sacha Chua writes about her baby&amp;rsquo;s Microphthalmia and says this &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll make an awesome pirate. Or cyborg. Or cyborg pirate. If she wants.&amp;rdquo; Woah!
I discovered Rains Of Castamere by Krish Ashok and loved it. Some looping happened!
@varungrover wrote argued for using better insults than &amp;lsquo;Presstitue&amp;rsquo; and I agree. I have had similar thoughts on the other insults he talks about.
This tweet thread got me thinking about speaking up, and standing up, and how people fail to do it, and what could help prevent these failures.
This picture of kids praying at Haji Public School gave me hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-03</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed reading the full judgement given by the Madras High Court in the Perumal Murugan case. The court said something on the lines of: not all art may be for everyone, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t like a book, throw it away. The judgement also made it clear that it is the responsibility of the state to ensure that things don&amp;rsquo;t go haywire using appropriate measures, and banning things left, right and center is not the way to deal with it.
This letter that a Law professor wrote in response to a student&amp;rsquo;s complaint about him wearing a Black Lives Matter t-shirt is superb!
Gabriel Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s post with a list of mental models that he found repeatedly useful has been great. There have also been some great comments on it! I wish to keep going back to the post.
Anaghs shared a summary of Brian Christain&amp;rsquo;s Algorithms to Live By and the books seems really interesting. Added it to my reading list.
This ad by BigBazaar for Eid touched a chord.
Black Mirror&amp;rsquo;s The Entire History of You totally got to my head, and if you are interested in the future of technology and human behavior, I highly recommend watching this episode, if not all the episodes. Thanks to @9 for the recommendation.
Calvin and Hobbes&amp;rsquo; Search is a fun project - search for Christmas, Life and Universe and enjoy the wisdom!
Sowmya Rajendran&amp;rsquo;s post on how the menstrual cup touched her life more than anything else after the Internet, was an interesting read.
The lights in the audience truly look &amp;ldquo;amazingly beautiful&amp;rdquo; in this Coldplay video.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post things that made me happy or touched my heart, each week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-10</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</guid>
      <description>Airtel&amp;rsquo;s response to @karthikb351&amp;rsquo;s write up on how they are sniffing and censoring CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s traffic in India was funny but sad, though, not totally unexpected. For instance, see @kingslyj&amp;rsquo;s version of how this might end.
I loved this interview with Amanda Palmer where she talks about her stolen Ukulele, Music, her dad and her baby and her love for life comes across, like in everything else she does. &amp;lsquo;I want to get a couple of T-shirts printed for me and the baby that say: &amp;ldquo;We are determined to enjoy ourselves&amp;rdquo;&amp;lsquo;, she says.
A year old but inspiring article on Serena Williams, shared by @baali. I like how she says, she&amp;rsquo;s opening the next door for the next person, like the many people who opened many doors for her. @baali also recommended this song from Neerja as background music, and I loved it!
Pierre buttin&amp;rsquo;s screenshot art is amusing and gives a sense of how distracted he is, each day of the week, and how distracted we are, as a people.
We were walking through the fields and bushes in Hampi and stopped at the gate of a private property. A bearded man with a calm look on his face asked us &amp;ldquo;Do you know where you are headed?&amp;ldquo;. And then let us walk across his beautiful nature home to the other side, where we found this amusing sign.
Finally, this Nike India ad on Women in Sport is great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-17</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</guid>
      <description>@9 shared this story about Peter Norman. Woah, so inspirational!
This conversation with Amitav Ghosh on his latest book The Great Derangement is pretty scary! He says, &amp;ldquo;You know that this great derangement is ultimately going to lead to a great unraveling, but to see it working itself out, day after day, in the news, it&amp;rsquo;s so terrifying. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s here, it&amp;rsquo;s happening. You may not see it a direct connection between the events happening in the world today and the climate in general, but that relationship does exist. In Syria, everything started with a great drought. The Middle East, this entire Mediterranean region, is going through a historic drought. And if you think about how this tumult in the Arab world began, it was with protests over food in Tunisia. So what we&amp;rsquo;re facing really, if you like, is a catastrophic convergence of natural impacts and human impacts.&amp;rdquo; I ended up buying the book at Bookworm.
This IndiaSpend article on how quotas have helped the disadvantaged caste students is a really well written article, with informative charts.
Kenneth Reitz released Episode-2 of Import This, a podcast that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of and ended up listening to Episode-1. I really liked the discussion on being considerate to others in communities that you are part of. The quote that this episode ends with, &amp;ldquo;Software is all about the people. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss them. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss their experience.&amp;ldquo;, resonated well with me.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; how to be a wizard programmer sketch is rad! (tweet).
I watched the movie Blind Side (2009) with friends, and really liked it. SJ and Oher together, they are a blast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python reload and module dict</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/python-reload-and-module-dict/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/python-reload-and-module-dict/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to play around with Nikola&amp;rsquo;s code today and learnt about a documented weirdness of Python&amp;rsquo;s reload.
 Below are two versions of code &amp;ndash; ORIGINAL and UPDATED respectively referring to the orginial code and the code after changes. The code only has a PLUGINS list, which is changed in each version of the code.
# Work in a temporary directory import os import tempfile os.chdir(tempfile.mkdtemp()) # Module content, original and updated ORIGINAL = &amp;quot;# PLUGINS = []&amp;quot; UPDATED = &amp;quot;PLUGINS = [&#39;rss&#39;]&amp;quot; def create_conf_file(content): &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;Create a conf.py module with given content.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot; with open(&#39;conf.py&#39;, &#39;w&#39;) as f: f.write(content)  conf doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a PLUGINS attribute in the ORIGINAL code. It&amp;rsquo;s been commented out!
create_conf_file(ORIGINAL) import conf # PLUGINS is not defined in the module, originally. print(conf.PLUGINS)  The code for conf has been updated, but the module doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet have a PLUGINS attribute, since the new module isn&amp;rsquo;t imported until we reload.
create_conf_file(UPDATED) import conf print(conf.PLUGINS)  PLUGINS has the expected value, after the reload
import importlib importlib.reload(conf) print(conf.PLUGINS)  What happens when we revert to the ORIGINAL code, and reload the module?
# We write back the original file. PLUGINS should be empty! create_conf_file(ORIGINAL) import conf importlib.reload(conf) print(conf.PLUGINS, &amp;quot;&amp;lt;---Whaaaat!&amp;quot;)   The behavior is well documented, along with a reasoning of why it is the way it is, but you can trip over it if you don&amp;rsquo;t know. I hit a bug and was wondering if there was a race condition somewhere, until I read the docs for reload. On reload, the module dict is updated, instead of creating a new dict. Any values not redefined in the new code for the module remain unchanged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assist time</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/assist-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/assist-time/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes hang out on #org-mode or #nikola and answer questions. I usually am not able to answer off the top of my head and I look up docs or dig through the code. Sometimes, we find ready-made documented answers, but other times we end up contributing some documentation, filing an issue, submitting a patch or hacking up something for that super-special use-case.
Until now, I looked at this time as IRC time, which loosely translates to distraction time. But, I&amp;rsquo;m usually learning about the tools I use a little bit more. Even when I&amp;rsquo;m not, I&amp;rsquo;m helping someone do something they want to do. Sometimes empowering them to fix future problems on their own. And indirectly making the user community a wee-bit happier, and possibly the software a tiny bit better.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t limited just to helping someone on IRC. Helping out a co-worker do something that they are new to, or just adding a comment or editing a Stack-overflow answer may end up in the &amp;ldquo;distraction time&amp;rdquo; bin, just because you weren&amp;rsquo;t doing something on your TODO list. It needn&amp;rsquo;t be.
Taking cue from scorers in Football, I decided to call this time assist time and to try to start seeing this time as (semi-)productive. Naming helps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortful things</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/effortful-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/effortful-things/</guid>
      <description>That dense book you want to read but has been lying on your desk while you procrastinate on twitter. You know you&amp;rsquo;ll have to tune everything else out, and read slowly, word by word, trying to understand and make sense.
That vague blog post idea swirling in your head while you look at cat pictures, one after another. Distilling your thoughts and putting them down for general consumption is a lot of thinking and effort away.
That ${cool_programming_thing} that a talk got you excited about so long ago. But, watching talks and intending to start using it is all you do about it. You know its going to take a fair amount of reading, thinking and time, before you can really use it well.
Like all those squats and lifts you dread, these things are building your muscle. The thing about building muscle &amp;ndash; it needs effort and feels like so much hard work.
You can&amp;rsquo;t build muscles effortlessly. Go do those effortful things! Only if you care about those muscles, anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better styling bookmarklet</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/better-styling-bookmarklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/better-styling-bookmarklet/</guid>
      <description>Some sites that I like a lot for their content, have zero styling on them. I find it pretty hard to read when the lines are long and I have to read all the way on my screen.
I had a simple bookmarklet until now that just changed the width of the page.
document.getElementsByTagName(&#39;body&#39;)[0].setAttribute(&#39;style&#39;, &#39;width: 600px&#39;)  Kamal shared with me a recommendation for 7 simple styling rules that will make pages easier to read. I liked them, and modified my bookmarklet to use these rules now.
 Drag and drop the link below onto your bookmarks bar if you want to use it.
Better website
The code in a readable format is below.
// Create new stylesheet (function() { // Create the &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; tag var style = document.createElement(&amp;quot;style&amp;quot;); // Add the &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; element to the page document.head.appendChild(style); // Add rules from bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com var sheet = style.sheet; sheet.insertRule(&amp;quot;body{ margin:40px auto; max-width:650px; line-height:1.6; font-size:18px; color:#444; padding:0 10px; }&amp;quot;); sheet.insertRule(&amp;quot;h1,h2,h3{ line-height:1.2 }&amp;quot;); })();  Update [2016-06-07 Tue]: baali pointed me to Firefox&amp;rsquo;s Reader View which works well too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading-time based scheduling</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/reading-time-based-scheduling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/reading-time-based-scheduling/</guid>
      <description>I had posted a link to an poem written on Medium on a Slack channel that I use with friends. A friend said that she liked the fact that the Slack article preview had the reading time from Medium in it. She could decide whether or not she wanted to read the poem or any other article at that moment.
This gave me the idea for a reading time extension for my browser, or my feed reader or my bookmarks &amp;ndash; my reading list. The first version should be able to compute or extract the reading time for an article or a tab in my browser, and index them. I want to be able to specify the amount of time I will be able to spend reading, and be presented with something from my reading list. I think this would help with scheduling the reading of longer articles, and also to actually help me get through my reading list.
Reading time estimates that use heuristics based on word-count may not really work, and may do more harm than good. But, it may still be worth a try to see if it helps my reading habits in any way. A quick search pointed me to this extension, that can give the reading time for any page but doesn&amp;rsquo;t really do what I want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping AFK</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/stepping-afk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/stepping-afk/</guid>
      <description>In the past few weeks, I noticed three instances where I was forced to take a break exactly when I was ready to jump in and write some code to fix a bug or add a small feature. I had to step out of the house and take a walk to meet someone, etc.
I ended up getting ideas during the walks, which significantly changed and simplified how I would&amp;rsquo;ve implemented things, if not for those breaks. Even if I did end up zeroing down to those solutions, I am pretty sure it would&amp;rsquo;ve taken a couple of not-so-good attempts and much longer than it did.
Context switches are usually considered to be expensive for programmers, but taking a break at the exact time when I had all the required context loaded into my head seemed to help. It was also probably helpful that I was taking a walk, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any other inputs or outputs competing for the space in my head.
This got me thinking about doing this more deliberately &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about any experiences or any experiments any of you have done with this. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of Rich Hickey&amp;rsquo;s Hammock Driven Development talk and I wonder if this is a smaller/different version of it, and makes me want to try out the things he suggests more deliberately. If any of you has thoughts and suggestions, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>