<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letter on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/letter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letter on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/letter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Lost Letters....</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/long-lost-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/long-lost-letters/</guid>
      <description>A few days back I received a letter from a friend, via post! [I know most of you can&amp;rsquo;t believe this&amp;hellip; but ya.. its true..] I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have believed it too&amp;hellip; if only he didn&amp;rsquo;t tell that to me when we met online&amp;hellip; {He spoilt the fun for me! :-(} So before going to dinner one day&amp;hellip;(a couple of weeks back..).. I checked out the Hostel Assistants room for any post&amp;hellip;. and &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rdquo; was right on top of the pile!! [Now that I speak of a pile don&amp;rsquo;t imagine that a lot of people here get personal letters&amp;hellip; most of them were business correspondence, magazines or likewise&amp;hellip;] Neways.. it was a great feeling to even look at it!! A white envelope&amp;hellip; and my name on it.. in his most familiar writing on it&amp;hellip;[no.. i don&amp;rsquo;t get letters from him often.. we have been classmates for quite some time.. so&amp;hellip;] &amp;hellip; the stamp [A leapard cat!]&amp;hellip; and the two postmarks.. [of Pilani &amp;amp; Zuarinagar!! :-P]&amp;hellip; Holding the letter in my hand.. it felt wonderful!! [I wanted to read it right then&amp;hellip;. but went along for dinner&amp;hellip;]
After dinner&amp;hellip; and a little time in the Children&amp;rsquo;s Park&amp;hellip; [relaxing.. wid 9,UC,Voodoo n Ringo]&amp;hellip; I opened it! It was absolutely thrilling&amp;hellip; to see a couple of pages written in ink [he still uses ink pens!! ;-)]&amp;hellip; With full enthu.. i read the letter.. and obviously once wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough to satiate my hunger.. i went through it over and over and over&amp;hellip; [i wanted to scribble down a reply ASAP&amp;hellip; but we had waves and quark coming up.. so i waited for them to get over (I could&amp;rsquo;ve written another one right??)&amp;hellip;to get more matter into my letter..]
Why is such a simple joy of getting a letter from a friend [there is email.. but&amp;hellip; for me its nowhere close to snail mail&amp;hellip;] become so rare these days?? [Something that was such a regular feature of the recent past.. is almost extinct now!!] Telephone and the Internet&amp;hellip;. they are the culprits&amp;hellip; (are they??&amp;hellip;..) In today&amp;rsquo;s global village&amp;hellip; is post a bit too slow for comfort? Will survival of the fittest ensure the extiction of this wonderful species in the world of communication&amp;hellip;??
Is a letter just a matter of communication&amp;hellip;?&amp;hellip; Isn&amp;rsquo;t there anything more to it&amp;hellip; [Obviously there is&amp;hellip; otherwise I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be writing a blog-post on it&amp;hellip;I would never think of writing a post on an e-mail I get!! (unless it is superhuman.. or something..)!!] Aren&amp;rsquo;t we losing out on something wonderful??
To attract good fortune, spend a new coin on an old friend, share an old pleasure with a new friend, and lift up the heart of a true friend by writing his name on the wings of a dragon. &amp;ndash; Chinese Proverb
The Internet is so big, so powerful and pointless that for some people it is a complete substitute for life. &amp;ndash; Andrew Brown</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>