<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackerschool on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/hackerschool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackerschool on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/hackerschool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>org-drill for making it stick!</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/org-drill-for-making-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/org-drill-for-making-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Those who read the last few posts here, would know that I have been experimenting with org-drill (a spaced repetition extension to Org mode). I have been using the system (almost) religiously for the past 2 months, and I do find that it has helped a great deal! (in some respects). I have also spent a considerable amount of time trying to reduce the friction to put new stuff into the system, and am constantly on the look out for further improvements.
Using this system has definitely helped with retention, and I find that I can recall quite a few things I have read a few weeks ago, that I would normally have been unable to. Though, I can recall a lot of information, I have been having a feeling of &amp;ldquo;fragmentation&amp;rdquo;: the feeling of just retaining individual bits/fragments of information, while losing out on actually internalizing the knowledge; not seeing the big picture, etc.
Wozniak (the author of super-memo) warns against learning without understanding, and memorizing before actually learning stuff. I haven&amp;rsquo;t consciously added stuff into the system that I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand (when I added it), but, later it does feel like I have lost some connections or the understanding, and am only holding onto the fragments of information.
The problems as explained in (read: as interpreted by me from) Make it Stick appear to be:
 The understanding (if any) at the time of adding stuff into the spaced-repetition system is untested. It may just be familiarity masquerading as understanding.
 The lack of any spaced repetitions for the overall concept/understanding and actual repetitions only for individual bits doesn&amp;rsquo;t help retention of the understanding (even if there was any, in the first place).
  To work around this, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try adding questions that test understanding, to the system. The Super-memo team strongly recommends keeping the drill items small and easy to answer. This may be helpful in keeping each drill session short, but I would really like to add conceptual questions to the system, and see how it goes. I hacked org-drill to allow me to type out answers, before looking at the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; ones. This is an adaptation of a system that a fellow Hacker Schooler uses, and shared. Also, hopefully forcing myself to type out the answer will help me get around the problem of sometimes saying &amp;ldquo;yeah I know that&amp;rdquo;, then looking at the answer only to reaffirm the feeling of familiarity, rather than actually testing myself. I&amp;rsquo;m still going to continue adding quick and short questions that test &amp;ldquo;bits of information&amp;rdquo;, though. But, hopefully the additional conceptual questions are going to tie things together and help fill in the gaps. Lets see how this goes!
For those interested, my hacks to org-drill below. The code is really a hack, and welcome any suggestions on cleaning up the code.
(advice-add &#39;org-drill-presentation-prompt :around &#39;pc/org-drill-presentation-prompt) (defun pc/org-drill-presentation-prompt (old-fun &amp;amp;rest fmt-and-args) &amp;quot;A presentation prompt that allows capturing answers.&amp;quot; (let ((cb (current-buffer)) (heading (nth 4 (org-heading-components))) (entry-id (org-entry-get (point) &amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;)) (input &amp;quot;&amp;quot;)) (switch-to-buffer-other-window &amp;quot;*org-capture-drill-answer*&amp;quot;) (org-mode) (insert &amp;quot;# Hit C-c C-c once you are done answering!\n&amp;quot;) (org-insert-heading-respect-content) (insert (format &amp;quot;Answer: %s&amp;quot; heading)) (org-entry-put (point) &amp;quot;QUESTION_ID&amp;quot; entry-id) (goto-char (point-max)) (insert &amp;quot; &amp;quot;) (org-time-stamp-inactive &#39;(16)) (insert &amp;quot;\n\n &amp;quot;) (while (not (and input (equal input &amp;quot;&amp;quot;))) (ignore-errors (execute-kbd-macro input)) (setq input (read-key-sequence nil))) (switch-to-buffer-other-window cb) (apply old-fun fmt-and-args))) (advice-add &#39;org-drill-reschedule :around &#39;pc/org-drill-reschedule) (defun pc/org-drill-reschedule (old-fun) &amp;quot;Calls the original reschedule, but also archives the answer&amp;quot; (prog1 (funcall old-fun) (let ((cb (current-buffer))) (switch-to-buffer-other-window &amp;quot;*org-capture-drill-answer*&amp;quot;) (pc/org-refile-to-datetree &amp;quot;drill.org_archive&amp;quot;) (message (buffer-name)) (switch-to-buffer-other-window cb) (kill-buffer &amp;quot;*org-capture-drill-answer*&amp;quot;)))) (require &#39;org-datetree) (defun pc/org-refile-to-datetree (journal) &amp;quot;Refile an entry to journal file&#39;s date-tree&amp;quot; (interactive &amp;quot;fRefile to: &amp;quot;) (let* ((journal (expand-file-name journal org-directory)) (date-string (or (org-entry-get (point) &amp;quot;TIMESTAMP_IA&amp;quot;) (org-entry-get (point) &amp;quot;TIMESTAMP&amp;quot;))) (dct (decode-time (or (and date-string (org-time-string-to-time date-string)) (current-time)))) (date (list (nth 4 dct) (nth 3 dct) (nth 5 dct)))) (org-cut-subtree) (with-current-buffer (or (find-buffer-visiting journal) (find-file-noselect journal)) (org-mode) (save-excursion (org-datetree-file-entry-under (current-kill 0) date) (bookmark-set &amp;quot;org-refile-last-stored&amp;quot;))) (message &amp;quot;Refiled to %s&amp;quot; journal)))  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth2 demystified</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/oauth2-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 10:09:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/oauth2-demystified/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I was trying to pair on writing a simple app that uses Hacker School&amp;rsquo;s OAuth2 API, and hit a roadblock on the first step of requesting an authorization from the user. Once the user authorized my app, I would see an error that said, &amp;ldquo;The authorization server does not support this response type&amp;rdquo;. I was using a client library that I had used before, and the server was using a what seemed like a popular implementation for ruby on rails. Getting weird errors is not done!
I have used OAuth2 based authentication before, but the thought of using it always makes me a little nervous, just because
 I don&amp;rsquo;t understand it very well. Like almost everything else, there seem to be so many libraries for doing this in Python, and I&amp;rsquo;m never sure which one to use, or which one I used the last time around. Not understanding the protocol also doesn&amp;rsquo;t let me debug anything that comes up.  To fix this, I set about to read and understand the OAuth2 protocol. This blog post is an attempt to record it for future reference, and possibly act as a reference for others.
Why OAuth OAuth is simply a way for an end-user to allow third parties to use protected data, without sharing the user&amp;rsquo;s credentials with the third-party.
For example, an end-user (Jane) can grant a printing service (Printo) access to her protected photos stored at a photo-sharing service (Picasa), without sharing her username and password with the printing service. Instead, she authenticates directly with a server trusted by the photo-sharing service, which issues the printing service delegation-specific credentials. (example from the OAuth 2.0 spec)
Protocol Flow The flow occurs through a sequence of user actions, client requests and user-agent (browser) redirects.
 (A) Printo asks Jane to allow using Picasa Data. The request can be sent directly to Jane, but is usually routed via Picasa/Google.
 (B) Printo gets back an authorization grant, which is a credential representing Jane&amp;rsquo;s authorization or approval. The type of the actual grant credential depends on the type of request that Printo used.
 (C, D) Printo gets back to Google with the credentials it obtained in the previous step and obtains a token that it can use to talk with Picasa.
 (E, F) Printo asks for the desired photo with the token it obtained previously, and Picasa gives back the photo to print. Jane gets her framed photo!
  But before any of this happens, the client needs to register with the authorization server and obtain a client_id and client_secret, that will be used to identify the client making the requests.
Pythonized &amp;ldquo;authorization code&amp;rdquo; work-flow. The OAuth2 spec allows the authorization request/grant to be of 4 different types. It also allows some flexibility in the token type.
In my experience, the most common work-flow seems to be using an authorization code as an authorization grant, and using a Bearer type token. This work-flow is explained in the diagram below (taken from the spec document). This diagram zooms in, onto the steps A-D in the diagram above.
This python code snippet is a simple implementation of this workflow, using the Hacker School API.
 Conclusion I think, I understand the OAuth2 spec a lot better now, and hope that this will help others understand it, too. And more importantly, I won&amp;rsquo;t get nervous when I have to add it to my projects.
Also, oauthlib for Python seems to be a pretty thorough implementation of the spec, and requests-oauthlib seems to wrap it for use with requests. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this in my future projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>