<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 15:02:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurse Center, 2014-06-11</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-06-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 15:02:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-06-11/</guid>
      <description> Plan Continue with the Haskell tutorials, with additional reading from Real World Haskell.
Actual  Finished exercises 4 and 5.  Learnt about Type classes in Haskell and how to create them and make data types instances of them. Also came across a new algorithm of sieving called the Sieve of Sundaram, which was discovered by a student. Surprisingly, I never heard of it before!   Miscellaneous  A few of us had an interesting discussion about various places people grew up in and visited, and the cultures, etc. Idea: implement a GitHub dashboard for organizations (say, HS batches) that give you different statistics, and interesting graphs. (Use elm?) [Update: Tom is working on HS and GitHub integration. So, that&amp;rsquo;s perfect!]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Cue: Recommendations for GitHub Repos</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/github-cue-recommendations-for-github-repos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/github-cue-recommendations-for-github-repos/</guid>
      <description>If you aren&amp;rsquo;t already aware of it, I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who goes around saying, &amp;ldquo;GitHub is my Facebook&amp;rdquo;. I spend quite a lot of time on GitHub, browsing the work of various people, looking at loads of interesting stuff that people built. I keep jumping between people pages and projects using the Watchers/Watching &amp;amp; Followers/Following pages. This way, I do come across interesting people and projects, but the SNR is too low. I wanted a better way to be able to see stuff, that I find interesting. That&amp;rsquo;s how the idea for this Chromium app &amp;ndash; GitHub Cue &amp;ndash; was born.
@baali and I hacked on this, during the last few days and got it working. It works as follows, (from the README) &amp;mdash;
 Scrapes all the descriptions of the repositories being watched by the user. Key terms are extracted from this description text using the Yahoo Term Extractor. A list of languages is obtained, based on the languages of the repositories, the user if watching. GitHub searches are performed for a combination of 3 randomly chosen languages and 5 random key terms. 10 random repositories out of all these, are shown.  This is a very simplistic algorithm, but works decently for my purposes. Ideally, I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked to use a Collaborative Filtering algorithm, but I found the data to be too sparse, and the amount of computation to be too much to be done on the fly. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really interested in pre-computing stuff and putting it onto my server. I settled down to the next best thing I could think of.
I would appreciate any further ideas and suggestions. Thanks!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>