<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Notes on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/book-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Notes on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/book-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on &#34;5 Love Languages&#34;</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/5-love-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/5-love-languages/</guid>
      <description>I first heard of this book in a discussion on relationships amongst friends from RC. The discussion was quite interesting and the book received more than a couple of strong recommendations. So, I decided to pick it up.
Very simply, the book is codified common sense explaining what Love is. Gary Chapman, the author, started with the question &amp;ldquo;What makes you feel loved&amp;rdquo; and found that the answers could be grouped into the following 5 categories:
 Words of affirmation Quality time Receiving gifts Acts of service Physical touch,  which he calls the languages of love. He also proposes that people have a primary language of love, and a failure to speak to a person in their primary language would make them feel unloved.
The book is filled with anecdotes to explain what each of these languages means and how to speak them, along with practical advice and exercises to learn to speak each of these languages. Though the book has been written with couples in mind, the fundamental ideas in this book can be applied to any relationships. I feel like it has been helping me connect a few dots, ever since I&amp;rsquo;ve started reading it.
It has been totally worth my time to read this book. A highly recommended read!
Below are some of my notes. Feel free to suggest improvements (for readability and otherwise) on the notes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>