<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cricket on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/cricket/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cricket on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/cricket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Power Play</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/super-power-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/super-power-play/</guid>
      <description>My first Cricket match in a stadium. I regret that it was a T-20. I&amp;rsquo;m happy, though, to have got the darshan of bhaiyya a.k.a Sachin. Also, I did enjoy the energy of being in a stadium.
I was actually intent on watching MI vs. RR, but, junta voted in favor of the Opening Ceremony. It was a grandiloquent let-down, but for the fireworks. There was nothing really spectacular about the ceremony. A mediocre performance&amp;hellip; With the kind of money they have at hand, and have spent, I really would&amp;rsquo;ve liked something better.
The match. DC vs. KKR. DC lost a game that it could&amp;rsquo;ve comfortably won. It would&amp;rsquo;ve been a decent match to watch, if not for the stupid DJ-ing. The game looked so different from what I&amp;rsquo;m used to seeing on the TV. [The only thing that was exactly as I saw in TV was, the crowd drooling at the cheer girls.]
I was shocked by the amount of disturbance a player has to overcome, while playing. Has the &amp;ldquo;gentle-man&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; game turned into a &amp;ldquo;super-man&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; game? Between each and every ball, the DJ is either shouting some incomprehensible inanities or playing some crazy &amp;ldquo;number&amp;rdquo; at the highest volume. The batsmen almost had to wait for him to shut up, before each ball. Can someone tell me if these are perks that the third version brings with it, or if I was happily ignorant, thanks to the TV watching? The heart-beat sound in the final overs was ridiculously annoying. I was looking forward to one of the batsmen throwing his bat at the DJ.
Also, it&amp;rsquo;s a big joke to call this ground a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; for DC. It was nothing close to a home ground, in terms of the crowd. I don&amp;rsquo;t see Cuttack being any more homely, especially with the Kalinga Sena already passing crazy orders to the cricketers. DC will have to play exceedingly well to end-up anywhere near the top. But, amidst all this, I&amp;rsquo;m happy for the people of AP. With a huge electric-power crisis looming ahead, they have already saved (or produced) power worth 7 IPL matches!
Also, this is the end of IPL v3 for me. I&amp;rsquo;m done with cricket for this season.
ps: Trying out new wordpress features of Twitter, Facebook announces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>