<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Third Round.</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/the-third-round/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/the-third-round/</guid>
      <description>This post is just to keep up a promise that I made to a friend of mine (well, actually myself). Presently, its the placement heat in our campus and people are busy writing tests, waiting, giving interviews and partying. This post doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much to with all that though. In one of the interviews, I was called back and asked about my Cleft Lip and Palate1. The interview panel had concerns if I faced any serious medical problems due to this. I explained to them everything that I knew about it and they were convinced.
Later, I realized, I never explicitly did any reading on this issue or asked my parents/others about this. I somehow knew about it always. I probably learnt at all those visits to the dentist or may be sub-consciously, when I was a baby. It isn&amp;rsquo;t, though, surprising to me that those guys had some reservations about it. It&amp;rsquo;s not everyday that you see a guy with a Cleft, though statistics say there&amp;rsquo;s prevalence of 1 in 500 births world-wide. As a matter of fact, I myself haven&amp;rsquo;t seen another guy all my life (except for the pictures at my dentists&amp;rsquo;) (also, they weren&amp;rsquo;t too wrong in suspecting other problems, though they had absolutely no clue about this medical condition)
If you are wondering what the point of this post is, it&amp;rsquo;s nothing. It&amp;rsquo;s just a pointer to those interested in reading further on Cleft Lip and Palate.
 Cleft Lip and Palate &amp;ndash; Wikipedia ↩   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>