<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JP - 19th Century Politics &amp; 21st Century Economics</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/jp-19th-century-politics-21st-century-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/jp-19th-century-politics-21st-century-economics/</guid>
      <description>Can they co-exist?
 Economics and Politics cannot be de-linked. In the 20th century, Human kind has discovered what works best in Politics.  Role of State?  Public Order, Justice, Rule of Law Accident of the womb doesn&amp;rsquo;t determine the fate of a child.  Education Health care  Infrastructure  Transportation etc.  Natural Resource Development Social security  India  2% of global economy  Politics Success Story  Universal Adult Franchise on Day-1  a great adventure an enormous expression of faith US, Britain took ages  Retianed political freedoms intense electoral competition winners do not punish losers elected governement is truly in authority Maturity of federalism  India is a truly vibrant functioning democracy. Moderate growth of economy, and influencing the global economy
Dark Corners  Vote buying
 Poverty, Illiteracy
 Power struggle without reference to Ideologies/outcomes
 Only change in players, no change of outcomes
  Freebies after election
 Dividing based on primordial loyalties
 No sense that any party would make any difference
 Emotional Purchase is only available    Argument 19th Century Politics, Medieval Politics and Modern Economics cannot co-exist. One of them will have to give way.
 Comparison with China
 Argument against Democracy is detrimental to economies
 Autocracy - everything bad that happened
 Democratization - everything good that happened
 it&amp;rsquo;s more than just voting
 in some respects China is perhaps more democratic than India
    What India needs
 Art of democratization of our society
 even after we have 7700 words in the constitution on this issue
 We created over structured under powered local governments.
 recognize the merit of de-centralization
 link between authority and accountability
 understanding of link between vote and public good
 link between taxes and services rendered
 tax avoidance is a national sport!    Rule of Law
 impeccable system of law normative-ly
 weak, in practice
 simple elegant answers exist.
 administrative forms comission  Culture of VIPs, cronyism, &amp;hellip;
  Fight Corruption
 corruption in India is Ubiquitous!
 answers are self-evident
 institutional mechanisms   Electoral System
 Proportional Representation
 Presidential system
 Old fashioned - first past the post system needs to go
 One vote can change things
 Vote buying will continue
     Challenge  We need to set the house in order today What happens to one-sixth the humanity cannot but impact the rest of the world!  Questions Answer-ability of administrators Vicious cycle of politicians (get purchase) trying to change the system bad politics drives away good politics young people recognizing the centrality of politics deep engagement of middle class pursuit of personal goals along with pursuit of public good politics - improved only by better and more politics, not revulsion Telangana issue Our federalism has matured remarkably neither a cure nor a catastrophe it&amp;rsquo;s a practical solution some people are seeking if language is not a marker, what&amp;rsquo;s the new marker?  there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having markers
 some uniform principle
  big city is seeking a separate state-hood  could happen with another state
 how do we resolve it?
  Once these things are resolved, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what happens.  the real answer lies in de-centralization  Rule of Law and Democracy over-centralization has been our bane decentralization is a tool of democracy delivery of rule of law is weak  we have to set that right  freedom and economic growth are compatible - show this to the world! Maoist insurgency the only form of dissent is within the bounds of the constitution state and the people have every right and duty to control it hierarchy of principles - preserving of constitutional order Positive experiences during your term as legislator politicians are just another set of human beings. period.  do whatever it takes to stay in power
 they are not villians
 political framework   Conclusion We have the technology. The world is truly flat. We have the resources, to be able to fulfil all the basic needs of all the people and the potential of the country.
We lack are institutions, right kind of politics. They take a lot of nurturing. Let us be engaged. It is our future that&amp;rsquo;s on the line. Economic growth is spurring changes in the country. Communications revolution is helping bring change. The question is, What direction of change? I ask of you, to make a difference to the way the Indian political trajectory takes shape.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>