<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exams on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/exams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exams on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/exams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life &#34;In-gen&#34;</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/life-in-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/life-in-gen/</guid>
      <description>Another post, with nothing concrete to say&amp;hellip;
 These are just a few random musings, for those curious about my life and for the good health of my Blog which is so close to its death.. College (+ Hostel) is amongst few places, that everyone on Earth(&amp;amp; elsewhere) \*must\* get the chance to be in. There&amp;rsquo;s a whole new world out here, with hell a lotuva things you can do, Here and Only Here&amp;hellip; [I am not, by any means, talking of acads!] Projects. Yes they are a part of almost all my random stuff&amp;hellip; cos I just Love them, when they are self-assigned and off-hand. They get even more exciting, when the learning curve is Steep! Deadlines can be wonderful things, if only I learn to respect them. Lab-Tests, i guess, are amongst the most hyped tests in the World! They aren&amp;rsquo;t worth all that fuss. Grades ain&amp;rsquo;t everything in Life. Not even if you are doing Engineering! I live amidst /wonderful* singers, marvelous music composers, facile lyric writers, cool Hackers, amazing photographers, inspiring poets and what not. [Why the hell do people then, look just for the *&amp;ldquo;industrious&amp;rdquo;/ grade scorers?] Music and Sleep are Great Healers. Laughter, too, is a close competitor. GNU/Linux is addictive. More n more people getting addicted, everyday! RHCE&amp;rsquo;s got a pretty interesting test. Its rare to be interested in undergoing the torture of a test, ain&amp;rsquo;t it? Rules seem to be total crap, until you get the chance to look at them from above. Quark&amp;rsquo;08 coming up! Gottu gear up for it! Comprees?? They don&amp;rsquo;t bother me so much any more. Finally, for those who found all the above stuff boring and dumb&amp;hellip; here&amp;rsquo;s some food for thought &amp;gt; The Best things in Life aren&amp;rsquo;t Things&amp;hellip;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost Control??</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/lost-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/lost-control/</guid>
      <description>Caution: This post is just some arbit crap, that arose from some internal probing. Its utterly worthless for any reader other than myself. This could possibly even be classified narcissistic or whatever that&amp;rsquo;s called.
Presently, I&amp;rsquo;ve got tests going on and they are half way through. Considering this and the fact that its been over a month since I last posted, writing a post now doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense, does it?[If my blog&amp;rsquo;s been dormant so long, can&amp;rsquo;t it be so for a couple of days more?] But things I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to off-late, don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. [in the past, at least they made sense to me if not to others.] This post is just about that, going from being senseless to at least being less sense [and hopefully, to being sensible]
I&amp;rsquo;ve screwed up the tests so far, and don&amp;rsquo;t think will be doing much better in the others too. Even otherwise, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything good, anything that feels great, anything that feels right, in the past couple of months (years?? decades??) [except for one video with &amp;lsquo;the gang&amp;rsquo;, i didn&amp;rsquo;t contribute much though]. Let alone accomplishing something nice, I haven&amp;rsquo;t even been attempting anything decent enough. My priorities have gone haywire, or may be not, may be I&amp;rsquo;m just doing things that are very low on the scale or may be I&amp;rsquo;m not doing anything, things are just hapenning.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve slept through &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; classes both inside and outside the classroom I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed awake all night downloading some crap for my comp. I had been worrying about keeping my blog alive. Made numerous attempts to post something, even if its no big deal not posting regularly. Changed 4 different OSes in a couple of days! been ages since I last visited the Library. Slept through the morning lotsa times, even if I enjoy EBER-ing Bunked bathing just because i&amp;rsquo;ll have more clothes to wash!  The list is pretty long. It ain&amp;rsquo;t sensible to be putting down the whole thing here. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve just been trying to escape things. Running from doing important stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough. Its high time I do something about it. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to get in control of my life, rather than being controlled by arbit stuff like sleep, a blog, a grade, an addiction, a song, a cricket match, a rain, a meal, a game of carrom, a prof&amp;rsquo;s accent, a course, a test or other such trivialities.
I wish to get back on track!!
..to get back into the habit of doing things I love, at the time and place I like.
..to doing things that give me joy, in the true sense. Not momentary, passing pleasures.
Hopefully, with some effort, I will. (A nudge is all it takes.)
btw, if this post was a total bouncer, this is for you&amp;hellip;.
 Time is the wisest Counselor. Exams come in a close second! &amp;ndash; punchagan
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eber-yone!?!</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/eber-yone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/eber-yone/</guid>
      <description>Exam time now. Sleep time cut-down! [already compensated for, during the whole semester! :D] Getting up quite early during these days&amp;hellip;. [To cram in something at the last minute.. :P]
But all that kept aside, I feel great to be waking up early in the morning. Watching the Sun rise.. is a great feeling. The calm of the dawn, the chirping of the birds n the cool breeze.. Its absolutely amazing &amp;ndash; awe inspiring. Its a great experience. A rare one for me,though.. :( For the last four semesters, I have been a part of the owl-tribe&amp;hellip; staying awake till late in the night and doing all sorts of stuff&amp;hellip; [other than study - during the non-exam time&amp;hellip;] Its great fun staying awake very late in the night&amp;hellip; having fun with friends&amp;hellip; B&amp;rsquo;day parties, Musical sessions in Ringo&amp;rsquo;s room, Movies, Carrom-Nights, all-night Chats(online n offline..) and lots of other stuff.
But all this can be done during the day can&amp;rsquo;t it[The fun of doing it in the night is totally different though..]?? If I enjoy the morning times so much, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t I be enjoying it more often? If its such a great feeling.. to be waking up in the morning.. should I trade it with all the fun I have, late in the night?? Is it worth it? Like Voodoo believes, should I put in efforts to enjoy the sunrise each day?? Is it time.. that I try out the cliche&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Early to Bed, Early to Rise&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; [EBER &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s what UC calls it&amp;hellip; and hence the title&amp;hellip; :P]
Update: If for Fear, people are able to cut-down so much on their sleep, and work so hard, I wonder how much is possible for LOVE. I think this is the thing that drives all the great achievers&amp;hellip; the Scientists.. the Hackers.. the Artists.. the Engineers&amp;hellip; the Writers.. the Doctors.. and a lot of others&amp;hellip; I need to find something, that I would Love to work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning... to save a Sem!!??</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/planning-to-save-a-sem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/planning-to-save-a-sem/</guid>
      <description>We are less than a week away from our supposedly dreaded &amp;lsquo;test-1&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip; n i have no clue even about what the syllabus is, in each course&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Theory of Relativity&amp;rsquo;, of which i&amp;rsquo;m able to make no head or tail.. then there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Electrical Sciences&amp;rsquo;, which totally &amp;ldquo;transformed&amp;rdquo; my plans for this sem&amp;hellip; then&amp;hellip;SPM.. muP.. POM&amp;hellip; MT.. C&amp;amp;S&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;
There are loads and loads of other stuff too&amp;hellip;
Relativity&amp;hellip; Emacs&amp;hellip;. C++&amp;hellip; Python&amp;hellip; Table Tennis&amp;hellip; learning a bit of Music&amp;hellip; picking up practical electronic skills&amp;hellip; reading a few books&amp;hellip;(quite a few actually..).. and so on&amp;hellip;. [not to forget.. attending classes&amp;hellip; doing a bit of course related work&amp;hellip;]. The list seems only to be growing everyday&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve crossed out yet.. there&amp;rsquo;s not one thing that&amp;rsquo;s done to perfection&amp;hellip;[with a third of the sem already through!!] {I already get the feeling.. its &amp;ldquo;Another sem down the drain&amp;rdquo;}
But didn&amp;rsquo;t I begin this sem with plans to &amp;ldquo;rock&amp;rdquo; it?? Wasn&amp;rsquo;t I supposed to attend all the classes that I possible can?? What&amp;rsquo;s it that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for the past 5-6 weeks?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know!! I really can&amp;rsquo;t pinpoint what&amp;rsquo;s been achieved in the past one month or so&amp;hellip; [other than of course quite a considerable amount of sleep&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.]
Why are things so horribly out of place?? What&amp;rsquo;s to be done.. to get on track asap.. I wonder&amp;hellip; What should my priorities be? Why am I being overwhelmed by the things I got to do?
I realise this time of my life is as precious as any other&amp;hellip; (probably more&amp;hellip;) and i need to make the most of it&amp;hellip;. but what is that &amp;ldquo;most&amp;rdquo;?? [It&amp;rsquo;s definitely not sleep!]
I wish to put together,
all my time, energy and matter
to do a job, little
that will ob&amp;rsquo;ly be infinitesimal
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make me a hero
but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t amount to zero&amp;hellip;
to me, something tangible
definitely seems possible
because nothing is impossible
if there is the quantum of struggle&amp;hellip;
but it must come
before I get back home
needn&amp;rsquo;t create an uproar
but before the end of semsester four
[Don&amp;rsquo;t mistake this for a poem&amp;hellip; for it is not!! Its just some scribbling of mine.. which will keep me alive if at the end of this sem&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s nothing other than this.. which is tangible&amp;hellip; something concrete.. something &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo;able]
Sometimes I lie awake at night, and I ask, &amp;ldquo;Where have I gone wrong?&amp;rdquo; Then a voice inside says to me, &amp;ldquo;This is going to take more than one night.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Charles M. Schulz
Little Things.
Little drops of water,
Little grains of sand,
Make the mighty ocean
And the pleasant land.
Thus the little minutes,
Humble though they be,
Make the mighty ages
Of eternity.
&amp;ndash; Ebenezer Cobham Brewer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>