<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bookmarks on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/categories/bookmarks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bookmarks on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/categories/bookmarks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-09-04</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-09-04/</guid>
      <description>This week was a busy one, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really consume too much web content.
A colleague mentioned that he was reading the book &amp;ndash; The Millennial Project: Colonizing the Galaxy in Eight Easy Steps and it seemed to have some interesting ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across before.
The Berklee Indian Ensemble performed at the Bengaluru Ganesh Utsava and I went along with Sunil to their performance, which we thoroughly loved.
I liked some of Chet Baker instrumentals that I listened to this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-28</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-28/</guid>
      <description>I liked this article advising developers on having healthy relationships. Most of it is common sense stuff &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Whether it be a side project or main project, understand that sacrificing relationships isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it.&amp;rdquo;
I really enjoyed this article by Priyanka on how she started talking to Auto Drivers. She shares a bunch of stories of drivers she talked to, that makes me wonder how many more such stories just go unheard, because I don&amp;rsquo;t talk.
@scopatz wrote up a nice argument explaining why @github should add back BSD to the list of licenses shown on the site. It taught me a thing or two about BSD and MIT.
I enjoyed spending the weekend at @mavin&amp;rsquo;s place, discussing continuous improvement in life, among other things. Also, had a lot of fun playing Psyche. The game is so addictive, but the app is not all that great. Someone should make a more robust app for this, or something that piggybacks on an existing network service like Telegram or Facebook chat or Google hangouts.
Falling In Love At A Coffee Shop by Landon Pigg is a lovely song, that I discovered this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-21</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-21/</guid>
      <description>Vox has a nice short video on shutting up about the y-axis &amp;ndash; It&amp;rsquo;s long past time to say no to y-axis fundamentalism, they say.
The New York Times has a great visual history of which countries have dominated the Summer Olympics.
This story of Dipa by ESPN is an inspirational read.
An old post on a Frameless Geodesic Dome that Bruce Hauman (of Figwheel fame) built himself is very cool!
This article on India&amp;rsquo;s Gozoomo shutting down shop and returning VC money is heartening and gives me some hope about startups in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-14</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-14/</guid>
      <description>NYTimes has been doing some amazing visualizations for the Olympics and this time lapse visualization of Bolt&amp;rsquo;s 100m Gold is great!
The History Project produced a book called Partitioned Histories that tries to contrast the narratives of India and Pakistan on their histories using school history text books. What a great idea!
This video about the Sunshine Orchestra being trained and tutored by Rahman and his KM Music Conservatory is touching.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; posts on how to decide and think about what to work on are great. &amp;ldquo;Even reliably recognizing good ideas is hard!&amp;rdquo;, she says, and this resonates with me. Writing a release email as a way to think about why you are doing something is great!
Jasdev wrote about his monthly check-ins with friends. I thought they were such a great idea - simple, yet, powerful. &amp;ldquo;The only regret I have about these checkins is not starting sooner.&amp;ldquo;, he writes.
This Vox article on America&amp;rsquo;s increasing wealth gap along racial lines is really well done and thought provoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-08-07</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-08-07/</guid>
      <description>Great visualizations about how global temperatures have been changing in the last ~165 years. If you are still a global warming skeptic, you definitely must see them.
These visualizations of Michael Phelps&amp;rsquo; performances at Olympics over the years by NYTimes are great, too!
I came across these delightful videos (1, 2) of girls and boys playing cricket at Haji Public School. Look ma, no sexism in coverage of sports.
This (Telugu) interview of Dr Jayaprakash Narayan is truly inspiring. Also, YouTube recommended his conversation with Sadhguru Jaggi Vasudev, which was unexpectedly insightful, and covers a wide variety of topics &amp;ndash; spirituality, religion, social organizations, politics, socialism vs. capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-31</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Lots of Olympics stuff this week!
I really liked this ad - Rukna Nahi Hai - wishing all the Olympians a wonderfully spirited competition, at Rio. Go!
Brazilian marathoner Vanderlei Cordeiro de Lima, the man who lit the Olympic flame, inspires me with his spirit.
This story of Mohan Kumar from Ambattur, a Chennai suburb is inspiring. &amp;ldquo;Now I am on the relay team. But in the next Olympics, I want to qualify for the individual event. That&amp;rsquo;s my aim.&amp;ldquo;, he says.
@vandith recommended the Nike+ Training App to me and I really like it. They have some amazing workouts and pretty neat personalized workout plans.
Coke Studio Pakistan is trying a delightful experiment with their show this time &amp;ndash; they are trying to use lights and vibrations to let the hearing-impaired experience the music on their show better!
Sainath&amp;rsquo;s keynote at Film Writers Association conference was yet another of his thought-provoking speeches. He sends you down a spiral of thought, when he says, &amp;ldquo;How agonised we are when people die, and how untroubled we are by how they live&amp;rdquo;. I also enjoyed watching his (long) casual chat from an year ago, talking about his life and influences on him.
David Sassoon the founder of InsideClimate News writes about Non-Profit journalism, the need for it, and how to have more of it. He writes about it in the American context, but India has its own share of troubles. I consume quite a bit of news from independent sources, but don&amp;rsquo;t really contribute to keep them going. I should turn this around.
A bunch of residents of Urur Olcott Kuppam in Chennai responded to media&amp;rsquo;s broken coverage of TM Krishna&amp;rsquo;s Magsaysay award. I really liked how assertive they were about their role in the music festival, its role in their lives, and in clarifying how they see their fishing village as opposed to how the media portrayed it. They don&amp;rsquo;t mince any words.
You can find my older weekly posts like this here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-24</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-24/</guid>
      <description>This week was relatively quiet for me. But, here&amp;rsquo;s what I liked, mostly from my twitter timeline. If you follow me on twitter, there may not be anything new for you.
This short video on how Nima made it to Ultimate&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious tournament made me cry each time I watched it. And movies/videos rarely make me cry.
Sacha Chua writes about her baby&amp;rsquo;s Microphthalmia and says this &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;ll make an awesome pirate. Or cyborg. Or cyborg pirate. If she wants.&amp;rdquo; Woah!
I discovered Rains Of Castamere by Krish Ashok and loved it. Some looping happened!
@varungrover wrote argued for using better insults than &amp;lsquo;Presstitue&amp;rsquo; and I agree. I have had similar thoughts on the other insults he talks about.
This tweet thread got me thinking about speaking up, and standing up, and how people fail to do it, and what could help prevent these failures.
This picture of kids praying at Haji Public School gave me hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-03</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-03/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoyed reading the full judgement given by the Madras High Court in the Perumal Murugan case. The court said something on the lines of: not all art may be for everyone, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t like a book, throw it away. The judgement also made it clear that it is the responsibility of the state to ensure that things don&amp;rsquo;t go haywire using appropriate measures, and banning things left, right and center is not the way to deal with it.
This letter that a Law professor wrote in response to a student&amp;rsquo;s complaint about him wearing a Black Lives Matter t-shirt is superb!
Gabriel Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s post with a list of mental models that he found repeatedly useful has been great. There have also been some great comments on it! I wish to keep going back to the post.
Anaghs shared a summary of Brian Christain&amp;rsquo;s Algorithms to Live By and the books seems really interesting. Added it to my reading list.
This ad by BigBazaar for Eid touched a chord.
Black Mirror&amp;rsquo;s The Entire History of You totally got to my head, and if you are interested in the future of technology and human behavior, I highly recommend watching this episode, if not all the episodes. Thanks to @9 for the recommendation.
Calvin and Hobbes&amp;rsquo; Search is a fun project - search for Christmas, Life and Universe and enjoy the wisdom!
Sowmya Rajendran&amp;rsquo;s post on how the menstrual cup touched her life more than anything else after the Internet, was an interesting read.
The lights in the audience truly look &amp;ldquo;amazingly beautiful&amp;rdquo; in this Coldplay video.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try and post things that made me happy or touched my heart, each week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-10</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-10/</guid>
      <description>Airtel&amp;rsquo;s response to @karthikb351&amp;rsquo;s write up on how they are sniffing and censoring CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s traffic in India was funny but sad, though, not totally unexpected. For instance, see @kingslyj&amp;rsquo;s version of how this might end.
I loved this interview with Amanda Palmer where she talks about her stolen Ukulele, Music, her dad and her baby and her love for life comes across, like in everything else she does. &amp;lsquo;I want to get a couple of T-shirts printed for me and the baby that say: &amp;ldquo;We are determined to enjoy ourselves&amp;rdquo;&amp;lsquo;, she says.
A year old but inspiring article on Serena Williams, shared by @baali. I like how she says, she&amp;rsquo;s opening the next door for the next person, like the many people who opened many doors for her. @baali also recommended this song from Neerja as background music, and I loved it!
Pierre buttin&amp;rsquo;s screenshot art is amusing and gives a sense of how distracted he is, each day of the week, and how distracted we are, as a people.
We were walking through the fields and bushes in Hampi and stopped at the gate of a private property. A bearded man with a calm look on his face asked us &amp;ldquo;Do you know where you are headed?&amp;ldquo;. And then let us walk across his beautiful nature home to the other side, where we found this amusing sign.
Finally, this Nike India ad on Women in Sport is great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I liked 2016-07-17</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/what-i-liked-2016-07-17/</guid>
      <description>@9 shared this story about Peter Norman. Woah, so inspirational!
This conversation with Amitav Ghosh on his latest book The Great Derangement is pretty scary! He says, &amp;ldquo;You know that this great derangement is ultimately going to lead to a great unraveling, but to see it working itself out, day after day, in the news, it&amp;rsquo;s so terrifying. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s here, it&amp;rsquo;s happening. You may not see it a direct connection between the events happening in the world today and the climate in general, but that relationship does exist. In Syria, everything started with a great drought. The Middle East, this entire Mediterranean region, is going through a historic drought. And if you think about how this tumult in the Arab world began, it was with protests over food in Tunisia. So what we&amp;rsquo;re facing really, if you like, is a catastrophic convergence of natural impacts and human impacts.&amp;rdquo; I ended up buying the book at Bookworm.
This IndiaSpend article on how quotas have helped the disadvantaged caste students is a really well written article, with informative charts.
Kenneth Reitz released Episode-2 of Import This, a podcast that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of and ended up listening to Episode-1. I really liked the discussion on being considerate to others in communities that you are part of. The quote that this episode ends with, &amp;ldquo;Software is all about the people. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss them. Don&amp;rsquo;t dismiss their experience.&amp;ldquo;, resonated well with me.
Julia Evans&amp;rsquo; how to be a wizard programmer sketch is rad! (tweet).
I watched the movie Blind Side (2009) with friends, and really liked it. SJ and Oher together, they are a blast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/11/01]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-11-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-11-01/</guid>
      <description> 50 Ways To Love Someone | Thought Catalog
Go for walks together as much as you’re able.
 Foundations of Data Science
These notes are a first draft of a book being written by Hopcroft and Kannan and in many places are incomplete. However, the notes are in good enough shape to prepare lectures for a modern theoretical course in computer science. Please do not put solutions to exercises online as it is important for students to work out solutions for themselves rather than copy them from the internet.
 Asyncio
Curated content from around the net to get started with asyncio
 s16h/py-must-watch · GitHub
Must-watch videos about Python.
 josephmisiti/awesome-machine-learning · GitHub
A curated list of awesome machine learning frameworks, libraries and software (by language).
 About - Mastering Emacs
The blog will cover all facets of Emacs and will be suitable for beginners and – I hope – experts alike.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/10/10]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-10-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 05:24:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-10-10/</guid>
      <description> frog hop - technicalities: &amp;ldquo;not rocket science&amp;rdquo; (the story of monotone and bors)
The Not Rocket Science Rule Of Software Engineering: automatically maintain a repository of code that always passes all the tests
 Intellectual conversations - Image (500×700)
    When You&amp;rsquo;re at the Crossroads of Should and Must This is a story about two roads — Should and Must. It’s a pep talk for anyone who’s chosen Should far too long — months, years, maybe a lifetime, and feels like it’s about time they give Must a shot.
 Black Triangles And when progress seems a little slow because you are doing a bunch of hardcore architecture work, just remember it’s a black triangle.
 motivation and unstructured time: successes and failures - alyssa frazee
some of the tactics I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to get myself into &amp;ldquo;working mode.&amp;rdquo;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/08/15]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-08-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 22:07:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-08-15/</guid>
      <description> Code is not literature
The ideal presentation should be aimed at an audience of gentleman and lady programmers—smart, and generally capable but without, necessarily, any specific knowledge of the domain from which the code comes. Presentations should provide enough context for the audience to to understand what the code is and should explain any details of the implementation language that may be obscure to the average programmer.
 Summary Report: Git Repository Disruption Incident of Nov 10th | Jenkins CI
As reported in various places, there was an incident in early November where commits in our Git repositories have become misplaced temporarily by accident. By the mid next week we were able to resurrect all the commits and things are back to normal now.
As there are many confusions and misunderstandings in people’s commentary, we wrote this post to clarify what exactly happened and what we are doing to prevent this.
 a/esr-sharing
I used to worry about what would happen if Linus got hit by a truck. With all respect, I still worry about what will happen if the complexity of the kernel exceeds the scope of your astonishing native talent before you grow up.
 Overview | Adafruit&amp;rsquo;s Raspberry Pi Lesson 5. Using a Console Cable | Adafruit Learning System
In this lesson you will learn how to remote control your Raspberry Pi with a console cable.
 A German Guy Wants to Give You a Bunch of Money for Nothing | VICE United States
After he stopped working earlier this year to live off the $1,300 he makes from his startup each month, Bohmeyer says his life has radically changed. So he started “My Basic Income”, a new initiative looking to raise enough money to pay someone $1,300 a month for a year, no strings attached.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/06/10]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-06-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-06-10/</guid>
      <description> Marss86
MARSSx86 (MARSS for short) is a tool for cycle accurate full system simulation of the x86-64 architecture, specifically multicore implementations. Our goal is to create a simple yet efficient full system architectural simulation environment based on existing tools.
 What 50 pounds of clay can teach you about design — Medium
while the “quantity” group was busily churning out piles of work”and learning from their mistakes”the “quality” group had sat theorizing about perfection, and in the end had little more to show for their efforts than grandiose theories and a pile of dead clay.
 metablog: Why I don&amp;rsquo;t mock
So don&amp;rsquo;t mock. Because it&amp;rsquo;s impolite to not listen to what your code is trying to tell you.
 Where&amp;rsquo;s the value in open source? | Opensource.com
Open source is about the people involved. Code can be replaced, re-written, even removed completely, and the project will continue to move forward. The open source community is made up of people who have dedicated their time and their life to see its success.
 I Recommend These for Learning Haskell
A friend of mine recommends reading 3 calculus books to learn calculus. I generalize it to reading from 3 sources to learn anything. I also postulate a law: the 3rd source you read is the best.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/05/19]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-05-19/</guid>
      <description> The Meaning of Life | Derek Sivers
Socrates said the unexamined life is not worth living. What about the forgotten life?
 Advice for ambitious 19 year olds - Sam Altman
The best people always seem to be building stuff and hanging around smart people, so if you have to decide between several options, this may be a good filter.
 Resources
There are many coaching resources available for coaches and players to help develop Ultimate programs and improve skills.
 Coaches Here is a list of resources for coaches and, of course, team captains, players, PE teachers, or anyone else who wants to teach skills, find a team to coach, or learn drills, plays, and strategy.
 17 People On The One Book You Should Definitely Read This Summer | Thought Catalog I figured I’d ask some young #tastemakers to share their suggestions with the world.
The list below is rather diverse in style — from comedy, to business, to self-help, to fantasy, to classic literature-y books that you could smartly reference at “functions,” there might just be something for everyone.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/05/04]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-05-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-05-04/</guid>
      <description> Learning Rust | Mauveweb
I also spent some time working out how to call Rust code from Python, which would allow me to use both languages to their strength in the same project.
 KEEGAN: The Opposite of Loneliness | Cross Campus
The notion that it’s too late to do anything is comical. It’s hilarious. We’re graduating college. We’re so young. We can’t, we MUST not lose this sense of possibility because in the end, it’s all we have.
We don’t have a word for the opposite of loneliness, but if we did, I’d say that’s how I feel at Yale. How I feel right now. Here. With all of you. In love, impressed, humbled, scared. And we don’t have to lose that.
We’re in this together, 2012. Let’s make something happen to this world.
 Raise Your Game: Day 1 - Skyd Magazine
This article is Part 1 in a 5 part series from Ben Wiggins on succeeding in the sport of Ultimate.
 Why I won’t work for Google | qnrq
“Gentlemen do not read each other’s mail.” – Henry L. Stimson
 This Young Mother Is Giving Up On Her Kids And I Don&amp;rsquo;t Blame Her.
My kids are not the center of my world because I love them enough not to allow them to be.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/04/29]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-04-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-04-29/</guid>
      <description> John Resig - Write Code Every Day
Inspired by the incredible work that Jennifer Dewalt completed last year, in which she taught herself programming by building 180 web sites in 180 days, I felt compelled to try a similar tactic: working on my side projects every single day.
 Debug your programs like they&amp;rsquo;re closed source! - Julia Evans
My favorite way to learn more, honestly, is to just strace random programs and see what I find out. It’s a great way to spend a rainy Sunday afternoon! =)
 Announcing AeroPython! - Lorena A. Barba Group
We now announce the public release of the 11 lessons that make AeroPython! Find them on the public GitHub repository.
 How I Came to Write D | Dr Dobb&amp;rsquo;s
Nobody could possibly work on compilers for 15+ years and not come up with ideas for language improvements. I tried out many language improvements in the C and C++ compilers, and they all fell flat.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t Deal With It, Fix It
I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that I have the power to fix things around me that I don&amp;rsquo;t like. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to just deal with it because that&amp;rsquo;s just the way things are. I have the power to shape the world around me. It&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of believing that I can change things. Just believing is all I need to actually take the first step towards taking action.
 Tyblog | SSH Kung Fu
What follows is a list for some of my use cases that leverage the power of ssh.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/04/11]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-04-11/</guid>
      <description> New York, 2014 at Mary Rose Cook
A video I made about Hacker School.
 Hacker School testimonial at Mary Rose Cook
The hours at Hacker School feel precious. This is the fastest period of learning in my life. I’m coming back.
 Dropbox Tech Blog » Blog Archive » Introducing Pyston: an upcoming, JIT-based Python implementation
The goal of the project is to produce a high-performance Python implementation that can push Python into domains dominated by traditional systems languages like C++.
 On not hiring
Hiring is hard. Not hiring can seem even harder, but often isn&amp;rsquo;t.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/03/23]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-03-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-03-23/</guid>
      <description> Replacing `import` with `accio`: A Dive into Bootstrapping and Python&amp;rsquo;s Grammar
At Hacker School, I&amp;rsquo;ve been building an alternate universe Python by overwriting builtin functions and statements with Harry Potter spells.
 Falling in Love With the Dark - Issue 11: Light - Nautilus
“The first time people come out for dark skies, and we get Bortle Class 1 and 2 here, it affects them deeply,” Carroll said. “They’re blown away. The connection with the stars is inside all of us, but it has been sequestered away.”
 Git is a purely functional data structure – Jayway
Git can be accurately understood as a fairly simple functional data structure. Instead of explaining Git in terms version control, we can see the ability to do version control as an emergent property of using that data structure. I think talking about Git in this manner will more accurately convey the simplicity and power of Git better than any comparisons with centralized version control systems can accomplish.
 Python’s Innards: Introduction | NIL: .to write(1) ~ 
This post marks the beginning of what should develop to a series on Python’s internals, I’m writing it since I believe that explaining something is the best way to grok it, and I’d very much like to be able to visualize more of Python’s ‘funky green gibberish soup’ as I read Python code.
 My Rust OS will never be finished (and it&amp;rsquo;s a success!) - Julia Evans
Not finishing your project doesn’t mean it’s not a success. It depends what your goals are the for the project! I wrote an operating system in Rust to learn, and I learned a ton. It’s not finished, and it won’t be.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/03/12]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-03-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-03-12/</guid>
      <description> Never judge a programmer by their commit history - Mehdi Khalili
Here is a few things I have either experienced personally or seen happen to great developers that led to bad code
 Statistical foundations of machine learning | OTexts
We are in the era of big data. The procedure for finding useful patterns in data is known by different names in different communities but more and more, it is grouped under the label of machine learning. This handbook aims to present the statistical foundations of machine learning intended as the discipline which deals with the automatic design of models from data.
 Howdoi – Instant Coding Answers via the Command Line - Benjamin Gleitzman&amp;rsquo;s Blog
One of my favorite collaborations to come out of the illustrious Oxidized Bismuth Blogger (OxBiz) ideation list is howdoi, a tool for instant coding answers via the command line.
 Elegance as a luxury
But once you see your brain as a CPU, then a more practical question arises. How do you organize the problems to maximize the efficiency of your brain…
 What Ultimate Does for Daughters | Bay Area Disc Association
In each case, it’s assumed that they are all the same kind of people — Ultimate people. These kind of people are family of a kind forged by lots of work, lots of experience and more fun than seems quite reasonable.
 Hacker School&amp;rsquo;s Secret Strategy for Being Super Productive (or: Help.) - Julia Evans
What if everybody asked questions when they needed help? What if helping people was everyone’s default procrastination method?
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/02/21]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-21/</guid>
      <description> ramonasuciu/ghostdrivertests
Basic tests with PhantomJS &amp;amp; GhostDriver
 Live Slowly | wikichen
In an afternoon, she taught me how to live slowly, to live better.
 Machines are better referees than humans but we’ll be sued if we use them « petermr&amp;rsquo;s blog
And the scientific literature will continue to be stuffed full of errors. And people will continue to die because of them.
Does anyone care? I don’t think so as no-one (ZERO) from a University has commented on my analysis of Elsevier’s restrictive TDM licence. They’ll just go ahead and sign it. Because it’s the easiest thing to do.
 40 Must-See Photos From The Past | Bored Panda
Perhaps the wars, poverty, fights for freedom and little miracles of the past have lessons for us that we can use today?
 Blog - Hacker School
Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve convinced you that gdb a neat exploratory environment for learning C. You can print the evaluation of expressions, examine raw bytes in memory, and tinker with the type system using ptype.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/02/12]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-12/</guid>
      <description> Learning to Code vs Learning Computer Science ← Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s Blog
Learning to code is merely teaching people to spell.
Computer Science is about what makes a poem beautiful, why alliteration is alluring, how iambic pentameter unlocks the secrets of Shakespeare.
 Need a Project Idea? Scratch Your Own Itch
how do you determine a need that isn&amp;rsquo;t being fulfilled and might be the basis for a project/business? Two ways. You could ask people what problems they have that you might be able to help solve, or (for introverts like me) examine what processes or services feel needlessly difficult in your own life.
 Generating a portrait from a hair: The work of Heather Dewey-Hagborg | TED Blog
Dewey-Hagborg’s work is super interesting, not to mention searingly contemporary. “It’s a very accessible way for the public to engage with this new technology. It really brings to light how powerful it is, the idea that a hair from your head can fall on your street and a perfect stranger can pick it up and know something about it,” she says, adding: “With DNA sequencing becoming faster and cheaper, this is the world we’re all going to be living in.”
 paperplanes. A Standing Desk Love Affair
Standing up all day can be tough at first, but I&amp;rsquo;m much happier working like that. Plus, when you finally switch off at night, you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like you&amp;rsquo;ve done more than just think and type.
 OUseful Info: The Cost of Meetings - How Much Return on Investment Do YOU Get?
If the counter is displayed during the meeting, then everyone can decide whether or not the meeting is generating a sensible return. Whoever has the courage to call off a meeting on the grounds it probably isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it should get 10% of the expected meeting costs saved to spend on a project of their choice (no meetings allowed ;-).
 5 Ways To Burn Out Programming
In short, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to burnout. Do these 5 things, and you can burnout too.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/02/10]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-02-10/</guid>
      <description> Abaswaram
A music podcast dedicated to sharing interesting things about creating music that most people rightfully care very little about
 Line Removal
Here is an interesting exercise in grayscale image processing, The goal is to remove some (nearly) horizontal lines from a scanned image, so that it is not obvious that the lines were ever there. The image is a pencil drawing that has relatively light pencil marks over dark lines that were printed on a ruled pad. The subject is Dave Carman, a venerable Exum Mountain Guide in Grand Teton National Park.
 Marius Ursache&amp;rsquo;s answer to Productivity: What are the best day to day time saving hacks? - Quora
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing and adjusting various productivity techniques for the past five years, read lots of books (most of them repeating) and here&amp;rsquo;s some of my findings:
 The Death Of Expertise
What has died is any acknowledgement of expertise as anything that should alter our thoughts or change the way we live.
 Amazon.com: 100 Books To Read In A Lifetime: Books
So many books, so little time. With this in mind, the Amazon Books editors set out to compile a list of 100 Books to Read in a Lifetime. We had a few goals when we started out: We wanted the list to cover all stages of a life (which is why you&amp;rsquo;ll find children&amp;rsquo;s books in here), and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want the list to feel like homework. Of course, no such list can be comprehensive – our lives, we hope, are long and varied – but we talked and argued and sifted and argued some more and came up with a list, our list, of favorites.
 Startup Riot 2009 Keynote
Do whatever you want.
Don&amp;rsquo;t take VC because Twitter did. Don&amp;rsquo;t piss off investors because 37signals likes to. Do whatever you want, whatever works best for you, what makes you the most comfortable and seems like the best idea. Do what you love.
What&amp;rsquo;s the worst that can happen? You&amp;rsquo;ll fail?
 The Egg
“No, just you. I made this whole universe for you. With each new life you grow and mature and become a larger and greater intellect.”
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/01/30]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-01-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-01-30/</guid>
      <description> Don&amp;rsquo;t Give Your Users Shit Work
Simplify. Don&amp;rsquo;t give your users the shit work.
 Improving Yourself is Easy
Being Ready is only accomplished after you&amp;rsquo;ve done something. Before you&amp;rsquo;ve done something, it&amp;rsquo;s daunting. After you&amp;rsquo;ve done something, it&amp;rsquo;s easy.
So do something.
 Matt Swanson - Making a commit with the Github API
Make a commit in just five easy* steps!
 Audio Fingerprinting with Python and Numpy
After a few weekends of puzzling through academic papers and writing code, I came up with the Dejavu Project, an open-source audio fingerprinting project in Python. You can see it here on Github: https://github.com/worldveil/dejavu
 Queue everything and delight everyone - 0xDECAFBAD
And, in the end, that&amp;rsquo;s really the purpose of a web-based content creation interface—accepting something as quickly as possible to make the user happy enough to continue submitting more. The other part of the user interface, retrieval, serves simply to get the original content distributed as fast as can be reasonably expected.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks [2014/01/17]</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-01-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/bookmarks-2014-01-17/</guid>
      <description> Who-T: On commit messages
Any software project is a collaborative project. It has at least two developers, the original developer and the original developer a few weeks or months later when the train of thought has long left the station. This later self needs to reestablish the context of a particular piece of code each time a new bug occurs or a new feature needs to be implemented.
Re-establishing the context of a piece of code is wasteful. We can&amp;rsquo;t avoid it completely, so our efforts should go to reducing it to as small as possible. Commit messages can do exactly that and as a result, a commit message shows whether a developer is a good collaborator.
 Akimbo Comics – Comics Everyone Can Hate - eat shit &amp;amp; die 202
&amp;ldquo;If you want to change your life, change what&amp;rsquo;s important to you.&amp;rdquo;
 Learn C The Hard Way
This is the in-progress free version of Learn C the Hard Way.
 The Anonymous Grumbler | A rant: 25-year olds giving free life advice
It’s your fucking life. Only you can decide what to and what not to do. If you’re going to be listening to every soul out there, you are going to lose your individuality. I say do what you want. You want to get married? Get married. You want to travel the world? Travel. You want date older men? Date. You want to have Shiney Ahuja’s lovechild? Have. The point is, be yourself. You can’t live the world through someone’s else’s dreams.
 awestruct: Automated deployment to GitHub Pages
This guide walks you through the steps of publishing a website that is built using Awestruct to GitHub Pages from Travis CI, automatically!
 The Most Important Code Isn&amp;rsquo;t Code
Documentation is the best way to communicate your thoughts to yourself.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>