<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts.. 2</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/posts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/posts-2/</guid>
      <description>These days my strolls, in the blog-o-sphere, have grown manifold both in their numbers and lengths. And with every passing step&amp;hellip; self doubts mount up. I begin to wonder if my blogs even worth its w8 in &amp;lsquo;seconds&amp;rsquo;. Like the thousands of others in this world, I could post something in one of these genres but..
 Techno Blog. [On various latest hardware, softwares, gadgets et al..] But I ain&amp;rsquo;t a geek to be able to post such stuff. If I ever posted something of this genre.. it would just be a copy-paste job.. isn&amp;rsquo;t of any great value, given the readership of my blog. Scientific Blog. [With the latest advances in various disciplines of Science] Again a case similar to the previous one. Not of much use Literary Blog.[Stories n Poems n other Creations.] I ain&amp;rsquo;t a creative being and rarely indulge in such creative acts. Would be foolish PhotoBlog.[Creative Pics/Paintings, Worthy of Display] I own no camera and don&amp;rsquo;t borrow one too often. Also haven&amp;rsquo;t got a very Creative eye to capture magic from the ordinary. Un-healthy Daily Diary. [An account of my day-to-day tidings] My life ain&amp;rsquo;t overflowing with adventures. I am presently leading a non-adventurous, pretty monotonous life that would be uninteresting to readers of all classes. Ruled out for the lack of utility. Current-affairs Blog. [An account of today&amp;rsquo;s, this week&amp;rsquo;s happenings] Not interested in being a Journalist, there&amp;rsquo;s already lotsa people who can handle the job better. Humour Blog. [Laugh and Let Laugh!] Again there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of it already online, and with a sense of humour like mine, the difference made would be Nought. Inspirational Blog. [Inspire others to do their best.] Its pointless preaching what I don&amp;rsquo;t practice. That would be hypocrisy. Information Blog. [Any info possibly..from pet-care to ethnic goan recipes&amp;hellip;] I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet crammed in so much into the super-computer on my top-floor to beat Google. A Mixed Bag. [Posts of multiple genres] Impossible. The bag&amp;rsquo;s already empty for every item of it has already been ruled out.  Do I still need a BLOG?
ps: Prevention of boredom-induced-insanity is the one and only genuine reason(known to me) for the continued existence of my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts...</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/posts/</guid>
      <description>I am beginning to notice something about my posts [ok.. there aren&amp;rsquo;t many that make it here.. :P] There are sometimes, when I feel I should write about a specific thing. I feel as if, there has to be a post about this, and there&amp;rsquo;s no way I can&amp;rsquo;t write about it.
But then I have limited access to net here&amp;hellip; and even less time when I&amp;rsquo;m alone, to write up something. I definitely cannot access net immediately, whenever I get that &amp;lsquo;feel&amp;rsquo; to write about something. So the post is postponed&amp;hellip; And later, when I think about it, or do get access to net&amp;hellip; it seems that topic isn&amp;rsquo;t worth writing.. or that &amp;lsquo;feel&amp;rsquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t there anymore..
I wonder if this would have been the case with my other posts too.. if only I waited longer to post them?? [But on reading some of the older posts I don&amp;rsquo;t feel so much that way&amp;hellip;] Am I being lazy?? [Is this how other blogs die down?] Is it that my life is dull and boring here (if it was so bad.. I guess I would&amp;rsquo;ve managed to write about boredom! :P).. and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing worth writing? [and I am just thinking of something to keep my blog alive?] Is my blog closer to its end than it is to its beginning? [I don&amp;rsquo;t think so.. its only a matter of time before I get back to coll.. :P] But is it the best way to be posting [instinctively&amp;hellip; immediately]??? Or is there something better that I should be learning.. that I should have learnt by now??
BTW.. why do people blog at all?? What&amp;rsquo;s the whole point of Blogging? [Yes, I haven&amp;rsquo;t still understood what it is.. even after about 30 posts&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Second Blog...</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/a-second-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/a-second-blog/</guid>
      <description> It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called a Second Blog&amp;hellip; because I won&amp;rsquo;t be posting any new stuff there&amp;hellip; I just started it to have a Wordpress experience&amp;hellip; I started it to know.. to compare&amp;hellip; and to choose&amp;hellip; I started it just for fun&amp;hellip; I started it because Blogspot may soon be blocked on campus!!!  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>