<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assist time</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/assist-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/blog/assist-time/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes hang out on #org-mode or #nikola and answer questions. I usually am not able to answer off the top of my head and I look up docs or dig through the code. Sometimes, we find ready-made documented answers, but other times we end up contributing some documentation, filing an issue, submitting a patch or hacking up something for that super-special use-case.
Until now, I looked at this time as IRC time, which loosely translates to distraction time. But, I&amp;rsquo;m usually learning about the tools I use a little bit more. Even when I&amp;rsquo;m not, I&amp;rsquo;m helping someone do something they want to do. Sometimes empowering them to fix future problems on their own. And indirectly making the user community a wee-bit happier, and possibly the software a tiny bit better.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t limited just to helping someone on IRC. Helping out a co-worker do something that they are new to, or just adding a comment or editing a Stack-overflow answer may end up in the &amp;ldquo;distraction time&amp;rdquo; bin, just because you weren&amp;rsquo;t doing something on your TODO list. It needn&amp;rsquo;t be.
Taking cue from scorers in Football, I decided to call this time assist time and to try to start seeing this time as (semi-)productive. Naming helps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>