<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julia on Noetic Nought</title>
    <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/julia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Julia on Noetic Nought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 10:46:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/tags/julia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurse Center, 2014-07-21</title>
      <link>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-07-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 10:46:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://punchagan.muse-amuse.in/recurse-center/recurse-center-2014-07-21/</guid>
      <description> Yesterday  It was exciting to have so many new Hacker Schoolers in the space. But, the excitement was kinda distracting too.
 I spent most of the day looking at shairport, and libshairport and trying to wrap it, so I can use it to get data for the spectrum analyzer via the Air-play protocol. I was able to call it using ctypes, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem discoverable.
 I also briefly looked at Julia and dwm, to try and port dwm to Julia. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like too much work, but is going to take me a while given how comfortable I&amp;rsquo;m with both Julia and C.
 Yaron Minsky&amp;rsquo;s talk on distributed systems was a great introduction to Distributed systems.
 After the talk, I spent a little time updating my notes from an old org-mode workshop to present it at the emacs user group meet up today.
  Today  I hope to get the spectrum analyzer to use libshairport and be able to play music sent through Air play.
 Spend some time talking to the emacs user group about org-mode.
 If I have any time, after getting this to work, I may play around with the dwm port.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>